Unknown: This is the point of
this presentations is to think
about kind of tools that you
have to increase participation
in your projects. And the best
way to increase participation is
to remove barriers to
participation. And so there's
this prompt in the slides, which
I really like to what will your
participation do for your
contributed, it's very tempting
to think about what are the what
are the contributors going to do
for me, but it's actually an
easier and more effective way of
working to think about what you
are in control of and what you
are able to deliver if you're
contributing. So open leaders
design and build projects that
empower others to collaborate
within an inclusive community.
That's what we're all working
towards over this training
program. And the goal is not to
ask what they can do for you,
but more to ask what I or what
we in the leadership can do for
them. And the reason that I
picked this this picture is, I
love thinking about the emergent
properties of a system. So these
are a bunch of ants, and they're
all working together. And each
individual land is not
particularly strong, but
together in when they are
coordinated, they are really,
really powerful. And I think
that's what I find really
exciting about an open and
inclusive collaboration. So this
is I'm sure you've seen this in
lots and lots of your talks for
the open leadership framework.
This is just sort of focusing
for you on the top right corner,
focusing on participation and
inclusion. Thinking about those
community interactions and
thinking about the governance
governance is one of the things
that people generally shy away
from, because they think that
the adults in the room will make
the decisions. And actually you
as the leader, even if there's
like literally nobody else in
your community yet, you are now
the head of that community and
you are in charge of decision
making. You're in charge of
delegating and devolving some of
those responsibilities, and you
are managing that governance.
And it's quite an uncomfortable
space to step into. But it's
extremely powerful, and very,
very rewarding when you do.
And it was a nice, concrete,
really fun exercise. And
potentially a really fun
exercise to just sort of have
conversations with people, as
you're talking about your
project is a description of an
imaginary person, who might be a
member of your community, they
might be users, they might be
contributors, they might be
funders, this all of those
different people that sort of
enable your community in your
project to thrive. And they
recommend that it's not a real
person, it gets a little bit too
sort of personal to have like,
lots of conversations about
specific individuals, but you
can absolutely use conversations
with real individuals to inspire
a general persona. Now, that is
not to say that your personas
should be general, it's actually
very powerful to draw a specific
and in this case, obviously,
literally draw but and then draw
in a figurative sense, specific
imagined people. So you've got
cat and Tom, here in the
examples, put a name on there,
because it just makes them a
little bit more human little bit
more relatable, give them an
age, give them an ethnicity,
give them a job, or maybe other
responsibilities. Give them some
skills, a level of knowledge,
think about what their
background has been. And once
you've done that, think about
their needs, their motivations
and their barriers. And you're
really trying to consider this
person as as a whole and multi
dimensional persona. So you're
not just dreaming up. Somebody
who's going to come along and
format your website, you're
thinking about a whole person
who may happen to have some
skills or be interested in
developing skills to for
example, format your website,
and what can you give to them
that is beneficial. So just as
some examples here, you've got
cast, who is an undergraduate,
an intern is really interested
in science, and he doesn't have
very much money. And Tom is 50
years old. He's a humanitarian.
He has a PhD. He has nine cats.
And he's got more of a
difficulty around time
constraints. And so the the
question the exercises, how can
they be part of your project? So
this is an example persona. I'm
not going to read through it
because you have the slides for
yourself but this is an example
Of how long the persona might be
to three paragraphs, something
like that. And I have to say,
one of the difficulties that I
find with writing personas is
that I tend to just write about
myself. So this slight line at
the bottom of cat also suffers
from a lack of self esteem,
essentially, like every persona
that I come up with says, she
doesn't feel like she has enough
knowledge to contribute or
something along those lines, is
very helpful to actually engage
a diverse and inclusive group of
people in helping you build the
personas in the first place.
Otherwise, you will continue to
just manifest like, different
versions of you with different
names. And so how are people
getting to join your open
project, and the personas are
fun, they're pretty interesting.
The pathways are the real sort
of powerhouse. So you need the
persona, in order to think about
the journey that people will
take to contribute to the
project. And I love this picture
of it is your responsibility, in
my opinion, as the leader of the
project to remove the barriers
to make it a nice, clear, easy
path, the cat can walk along.
So this is sort of going back to
thinking about that mountain of
engagement that malvika was
talking about, somebody has to
discover that your project
exists in the first place. So
how are they going to do that,
then they will come into contact
with it in some way they might
see you give a talk, they might
hear about it on social media,
they might have somebody else
reach out to them, what does
that look like, then they might
participate, hopefully, some of
them will participate. Sustained
participation means that they
keep coming back, they keep
participate. Network
participation means that they
are starting to bring in other
people and they're starting to
bring in other sort of linked up
projects, resources and other
communities that you start to
kind of link everyone together.
And then leadership is really
have sort of being part of that
kind of holding that
responsibility for the health of
the community. And, and thinking
about directing the ship as it
goes forwards. And here's just
an example of a pathway for cat.
So she might see a tweet about
Brazil as festival, buy a ticket
and take part in a training
program, turn up to a hackathon.
There'll be afterwards, right?
So if she hosted her first
Mozilla sprint hackathon, the
very discovery point, well, that
doesn't make sense, because she
can't discover on that level,
but she could potentially
participate first. And so you're
thinking about what each of
these levels means for this
individual person. And their
leadership is starting to go
into that, that mentorship and
that support and role. Now, I've
taken just two slides, I think
from another slide deck, which
is available for you to look at,
because I I probably have gone
over time already. And there are
lots of different ideas for ways
of people to come in. And I
think the best thing that you
can do is you can just ask
people, why they contribute to
other projects, or why they
don't contribute to other
projects, what their challenges
are, but mentored issues as a
really, really nice way of
getting started. So writing an
issue on GitHub should be a good
first issue or an issue that is
reserved for first timers should
take longer to write than it
would do for you to address. And
that feels really
counterintuitive, unless you
start to think about this, Pat
these pathways in this mountain
of engagement. So if you spend
time writing really good,
accessible, easy to achieve easy
to kind of draw a line and say I
haven't I have completed this
issue. issues. You can put your
name as a mentor or you can find
other people in your community
to say that they will kind of
particularly Shepherd this task
along and they are available for
answering questions, those folks
and try very hard to reserve
those issues, try really hard to
kind of keep them only for the
newest members if you can. And
if you have a good issue, we'll
have some information on how to
get started, where to find helps
and clear requirements. And then
making sure that it's got the
resources that votes and so you
can make sure to try and stay as
be as friendly as possible and
say thank you, welcome them and
give good consistent and helpful
feedback as best you can. So
rather than be tempted to
complete the task for someone
Try and solicit the challenges
that they're having, in order to
guide them to completion, it
feels amazing when you complete
a piece of work. And if you've
had someone support you along
that journey, it's a really
sticky in a good way, way of
joining in staying unity. Try
and think about just as sort of
some other examples from a
mentorship point of view. If
people are going to discover the
project, they're going to
participate for the first time.
And we're going to have first
contact them, they'll
participate. And then you need
them to stay or you would
ideally like a lot of them to
stay, to think about what you
need, what people will need from
you in order to stick around.
And these are just some of the
examples. Think about your
projects. And so working open is
being responsibly responsive
your community needs and there's
a bunch of different solutions
here. And I am going to finish
and let you kind of think about
how you would like your project
to succeed going forward.