Unknown: So we're gonna now
switch to the last part, which
is about contributing guideline
and code of conduct. In the
call, we have today Karen liason
who was our expert for this
part. But I'll go through this
in one minute to introduce what
this part is for and why we're
interested in that. So if we go
in the next slide, you would see
this over and over. And we will
be highlighting different parts
of our vision statement. So
building project for
collaboration within inclusive
community. And in the next
slide, you will see that we're
now moving to this part, which
is about building for
participation and inclusion. So
who's making decision? Who's,
who's delegating tasks? Who is
delegated to? How are we
planning our event? How is the
community management happening
and was monitoring what's
happening in the community. So
when we work in an open
community, it's all about
relationship. you depend on
community members who are
volunteers, we're working on
your project, probably beyond
their own personal work time. So
it's really important how you
keep them involved, and identify
who's the active member, what
are their roles, how you can
give them autonomy, and how you
can also keep the governance so
your project does not derail. So
in the next slide, a will be
what we are going to do with
this stock is to make you think
about how to create a positive
culture, how to think about
contribution and collaboration.
And please keep note of the fact
that this is going to really
influence how you're going to
write your assignments and draft
your own contributing guideline
and choose a code of conduct for
your project that's really
appropriate for your community.
So with that, I'm happy to
introduce Karen liason, she is a
researcher in, in Norwegian
veterinary Institute, and also
Chair of the carpentries code of
conduct Committee, which is
where I work with her. And I'm a
huge fan of her work. And I'm
happy to have her on the call
today.
Thank you so much for that very
nice introduction. So this talk
will have will focus on two
documents in in this context.
And that's the contribution
guidelines, and also the code of
conduct. So the important thing
to bear in mind is that you as a
project leader, you're trying to
build a community around your
project, you're trying to
attract volunteers to your
project. And these will have
diverse backgrounds, and come
into your project with different
different expectations. Now,
whenever you have a group of
people gathered like this, a
culture a group culture is bound
to develop whether you intended
to do or not. And this means
that you as a project leader,
you have to take initiatives
with regards to what kind of
culture you want your project to
have. If you don't, a project
culture will develop without
you. And this means that you
have to be make some conscious
choices regarding how you want
your community to build. What
values should your community
advocate? How do you want people
to interact with each other and
with other people. The thing to
remember here is that a project
is actually a lot more than just
its scope, goals. It's a
language, it's a shared set of
norms, it consists of people's
expectations to the project.
It's the tools that you choose
to use. It's the systems you set
up to make decisions. It's the
project identity. And all of
these things affect the health
of your community, the community
around your project, and because
of that, it will also directly
affect the progress of your
project. Now, how do you go
about shaping the culture you
want? There are two big things
that can be done in this
context. And that's to have a
clear set of contribution
guidelines, which will help your
contributors your volunteers
interact with your project. And
the second is to have a code of
conduct and these are two things
Important vehicles that will
help you as a product leader, to
communicate to your community,
how you want your community to
be. So, what we're trying to do
is to get people to contribute
to your project. It's in this
context important to remember
that your contributors are
people with their own worldviews
and their own stories. We need
to take this into consideration
when we're trying to build a
welcoming atmosphere so that
people will want to contribute
to your project. One such
community, I'll show an example
here is the carpentries.
Community. That's the community
that I personally am part of.
And we've taken a very proactive
stance when it comes to
community to project culture.
And I'll show this through both
the contribution guidelines and
the code of conduct that this
project has set up. So first, to
the contributing documents. So
first of all, these are readily
available within each GitHub
repo for each set of teaching
materials, and we do this to
make sure that it's easy for
people to find them. So the
contributing guidelines have to
first of all, they have to be
easy to find, if you can't find
them, you can't use them. So
what kind of information should
these kinds of documents
contain? Should they contain
information that various kinds
of people might want to know? So
for your contributors to people,
you want to help you out with a
project, you want to tell them
the process and conventions that
they'll need to follow when
they're making a contribution.
It should also detail how they
are expected to interact with
other members of the community.
When it comes to the project
consumers, these are the people
who might want to build off the
work that you've done, it should
clearly detail how they can
remix and reuse your work in
their own projects. And this
file should give them the give
them a sense of how to do that,
and what's allowed to do with
the material.
You as a project owner, you will
want to create and maintain this
file. And you'll you should make
sure that you keep this file
updated. One good thing about
writing and creating this file
is that it will help sort out
for yourself how how you can
have good interactions in your
community. So let's look here.
For the carpentries we have in
addition to the contributing
document in itself, we've also
specifically set up web pages,
which will help people interact
with our community. So this is
shown here is a list of
channels, communication channels
into our projects, which helps
people help channel people into
the parts of the product that
they might want to contribute
to. And this makes it easy for
someone new to find out what
they can do. And this is this is
one very good way of doing that.
Okay, now we'll move on to the
issue of a code of conduct. Now,
the basis for this is that to
have a well functioning
community, we need to take into
consideration that the other
feature people that are in our
project are not carbon copies of
ourselves. If you're lucky,
you're able to build a diverse
community, for your project. And
a diversity of people and
opinions will make your product
stronger. It will help your
project be original and
adaptable and durable in the
long run. The issue then becomes
what if something happens in
your community that shouldn't
and this is where a code of
conduct comes into play. A Code
of Conduct speaks to what is
accepted and what is not.
accepted in your community. It
also speaks to what do we as a
community do when something that
is not accepted happens? So why
do you? Why do you actually
really need a code of conduct?
Well, there are really three
things that our code of conduct
does in your community, the role
they play place. First of all,
it helps invite new people to
your project, simply by saying,
Hi, we're here, please interact
with us. It also sets clear
expectations for community
members. It tells them how we
want people to behave, what kind
of interactions we want in our
community. Last but not least,
and probably most important, a
having a code of conduct tells
your community that you care
about it, it tells them that
their well being is important to
your product. And that is
probably more is more important
on a community context. More
important than anything else.
So here, links in the
presentation that I'm assuming
that you'll get access to, there
are some examples of code of
conduct. And I'll now show you
the carpentries code of conduct.
So you can have a look at that.
So if we see here at the top, I
not Can you see my mouse? Okay,
so here at the top, this is the
welcoming part. But we quickly
move into the setting
expectations part by clearly
stating that by interacting in
this community by becoming a
part of it, we expect you to
follow our code of conduct. And
we clearly say that not doing so
well have consequences. Next,
below here, we have described
some a few examples of behaviors
that we encourage in our
community. And this also helps
set expectations for our
members. Another thing that
you'll see in our code of
conduct is that we have clear
guidelines for how to deal with
incidents, if something happens,
we have guidelines and
procedures for what to do. And I
want to emphasize here that it's
very important to actually
enforce your code of conduct.
The only thing that is worse
than not having one is not
enforcing it. Because you have
if you have one and you don't
enforce it, what you're telling
people is that you actually
actively don't care about the
victim wellbeing of your
community. Okay, so how do you
get started on getting a code of
conduct? Well, you need to start
to think about what values you
want your community to have.
What kind of behaviors Would you
like to see in your community.
Also, think about how you want
to process an incident if
something should happen, and
what the consequences should be.
Last but not least, you as a
project leader, you will have to
accept that this is something
you have to deal with.
Humanity starts with culture, it
starts with you. And your
attitude towards these kinds of
things will permeate your
project and some takeaways at
the end. encourage those who
have have good practice in your
community. Those should follow
the follow the contribution
guidelines in a good way. Those
who help help build a good
community. Also, make sure to
interact with your community to
build these things. This will
help help ensure buy in from
your community members also set
up a process for how to how to
deal with current akoto called
own conduct issues. and
communicate these guides these
processes clearly to your
community members. My last tip
is really, if you if at all
possible, don't write your own
code of conduct. Find a code of
conduct that you like and copy
and adapt that one because
committee Code of Conduct
documents can be quite
complicated to write. There are
a lot of facets to think about.
And that is it for me.