Unknown: What I am going to talk
about today is more about
inclusive design, the importance
of thinking about inclusion in
design, and a bit about
unconscious bias and how that
seeped into my work. So like I
said, I'm a software developer,
that's what my day job. But
these ideas are broadly
applicable, and they apply to
science just as much as anything
else. So we've already talked
about it a bit already. On the
call cycle, I can, but let's
just make sure I'm in sort of
define what I mean by inclusion.
Because I think it's one of
these words, that means a lot of
different things. We hear it in
all the context, it's next
diversity accessibility. Let's
break down and make sure we're
on the same page. So imagine you
were holding a party. And I want
you to imagine, and please don't
do it. Because if you can't tell
I wrote this slide more than a
week ago. If you send
invitations far and wide, then
that's diversity, you're
inviting a wide range of people
to participate, but not really
giving them any reason why they
might enjoy your party.
Inclusion is about making sure
people actually have a good time
at the party. And that might
mean things like making sure you
have a range of drinks
available, making sure there's
food that everybody can eat,
making sure you spend time with
somebody who travel a long way
out of town to come and see you.
It's making the effort to ensure
that people feel included and
welcomed. And when people feel
more included and they feel
welcomed, then they're more
comfortable to share their
experiences, their ideas, their
fears, their concerns, to
challenge the status quo. And of
course, those all have benefits
for our communities. To pick you
looking at a world, for example,
like science, obviously,
science, we care about having
lots of good ideas. But we don't
know if an idea is going to be
good until we until you know
until after the fact so we need
to get as many ideas as
possible. And making sure we
have a really diverse range of
people contributing is one way
to do that. That's what
inclusion is include. That's why
inclusion is important. And I
think we'd all agree, inclusion
is a nice thing to have. But it
doesn't always happen in
practice, right? in many
communities, in many groups,
people feel excluded, they feel
unsafe, they feel forgotten,
they feel ignored. And so
assuming this isn't malice,
assuming people don't want to do
this, why does this happen? So
one of the reasons One of the
things malvehy cook wanted me to
talk about is this idea of
unconscious bias. Now, I
personally don't actually love
the term, because I think it has
quite a negative stigma. It can
feel very negative, very
critical. You know, it feels
like it's a criticism of us that
we have unconscious biases that
makes us bad people. And
obviously, yo was asking, you
know, do anyone feel slightly
uncomfortable at the results,
the unconscious bias test? I
think it's a shame because I
think there is a useful idea
here. But often it gets lost in
the in the stigma and the
criticism. So let's just talk
about pattern matching. Okay,
humans are very good at pattern
matching, we look at the way we
use it to construct rules about
how we think the world works.
Everything is a or b, if P then
Q, either x or y, and so on. And
the rules we imagine are always
correct, right, we might learn
something's a trial of the world
behaves in simple way, and then
grow up and we discover the
world actually is a bit more
complicated than that. And the
rules need adaptation. So the
more of the world we see, the
more we have to update our rules
based on new ideas and
information. And that's just
part of being human. Now, can we
come up with these rules,
subconsciously, you know, we're
very good at bringing optimize
to coming up with these
patterns, we don't realize how
many we've internalized, we
don't notice we've adopted a
rule until something breaks it.
And that's what unconscious
biases, it's when we imagine the
world follows a particular rule.
don't even realize we're
following that rule. And that
rule is inadvertently excluding
or overlooking somebody. And
when we act upon those rules,
these incorrect rules, we can do
things that make people feel
excluded. So having unconscious
bias, I don't see as a moral
judgment on us. It's just as
innate pattern magic logic
that's gone a bit wrong. So
let's look at a couple of
examples. First of all,
smartphones, so we've all got
smartphones, I imagine many of
you use them to record video.
And if you're recording video,
while you might be uploading it
to YouTube. So if you go back
about five or six years, when
YouTube released their first
upload app for the iPhone, they
discovered about five or 10% of
their users were uploading the
video wrong, the wrong way up.
And you know, was this some sort
of design trend? Was it a
fashion statement? Was it a Was
it a mistake, actually was none
of those things, it was a
misunderstanding on the part of
the YouTube Developers how
people use their phones. So if
you look at the picture, we can
see the person is holding the
phone in their left hand. And
that means their right hand free
to come along and actually
interact with the controls. Now
imagine so we could imagine that
this person probably their right
hand dominant, this is probably
a right handed user. Now imagine
that a left handed user is
trying to shoot video. Well,
they to hold the phone in their
right hand
and manipulate it with their
left hand, meaning they'd be
holding the phone the other way
up. And YouTube's mostly right
handed development team hadn't
thought of this use case they've
never considered that somebody
might be holding their phone,
the Otherwise, when they tried
to record videos, they'd
internalize the incorrect rule.
If somebody is recording video,
then they hold their phone in
this orientation. It wasn't
until they have left handed
users, they realized their
mistake.
That's one example. That's
another. So I know the Okay,
you've done a bunch of these
calls, I know you've done some
work with
Git and GitHub are both very
widely used piece of software, I
use them all day. And one of the
great features of Git is that
gives gives us an immutable
record of our changes, it's
impossible to change history and
get without it being obvious,
very disruptive. And this is a
good thing creates an audit
trail, create stable history,
and so on and so forth. That
immutable history includes your
code, your commit message, the
date, and your name, the
committee's name is permanently
baked into the history of a git
repository. And this can cause
problems when people change
their names, because now their
old name is preserved forever in
this good history. And it's
incredibly disruptive to change
it. And so, you know, I've got
trans friends who've changed
their name. And they have to
choose between abandoning a
large body of work, and no
longer associated with the
project that they worked on. Or
accepting that the get history
forever going to outnumbers
crowns. Okay, there's this on
effect, unintended side effect
of get making the name and
immutable part of the history
that has this format down the
line. Now, again, I don't think
this was malice from the get
developers, they just
internalized an incorrect rule.
Nobody ever changed their name.
It didn't occur to them, this
design choice might exclude
users. But now 10 years later,
we're all stuck with it. Second
example. Next, the second
example from my workplace. I
work at wellcome collection,
which is a Museum and Library
about the history of human
health and medicine. And one of
the things we have is we have
this wonderful collection of
digital historical images.
These images to make them easier
for people to find, maybe an
algorithm could tell us that
these pictures are a man, a
mountain, a market or a mole.
Maybe you could do all that
tagging for us and say the human
the work. But we got to be
careful because machine
learning. It's good for many
things. But one of the things it
does is it takes our pattern
matching rules, our unconscious
biases, and it tiles from up to
a level. If humans are good at
pattern matching machines are
amazing. And there are plenty of
stories about algorithms
replicating unconscious biases
in the training sets in the
training set of images they're
given. So a couple of years
back, Google got in hot water
because they tagged images of
black users as gorillas, which
is incredibly insensitive.
Microsoft and others companies
had similar issues where their
motion capture software doesn't
attach to people. And again, you
sort of they've internalized
these bad rules about what does
a collection of images look like
all people have light colored
skin, obviously not correct. But
that's how that that can end up
having implications that we
don't realize. Finally, let's
move out of the digital realm
and look at a physical examples,
motor cars. So modern cars are
extremely safe, they're subject
to rigorous crash testing,
they're packed with safety
features, we can see here two
cars being tested. pretty
serious impact here, but the
passenger compartment in both
cars remains relatively intact.
So very safe. But repeated
studies showed that women are
more likely to die in car
accidents. And the reason for
that is because fairly recent
until fairly recently, crash
tests only featured male body
test dummies, they're actually
based on a 50th percentile
American man, that was the exact
body shape and size that was
used in all crash tests, safety
testing. And so that was the
basis on which safety features
were designed. Now women,
especially smaller women, have a
different size and shape to a
lot of to this 50th percentile
man. And so they experienced the
forces in a collision in quite a
more severe way. And the car
industry is now using a wide
variety of crash test dummies,
but but obviously it doesn't
hurt to help anyone who's
already been injured in an
accident. And it's gonna take
years before that inequality is
worked out of the of the pool of
existing cars. So what's the
message here? inclusion has to
be part of our design process.
It's not something we can add
later. It's not something we
sprinkle on top like icing
sugar. It has to be something we
think about throughout our works
throughout our design process.
You know, you look at some of
those examples. They're all
embarrassing, or annoying, but
in some cut, but it was hard to
impossible to fix some of those,
you know, YouTube, they've got a
bug, they ship it a fix, they
updated. People forget about it
fairly quickly. But those cars,
those cars with the incorrect
safety features, they're going
to take years or decades to
filter out and with something
like get that is permanently
baked in forever, we can never
change that. So we need to think
about inclusion throughout. And
it's got to be part of our
design process can be something
we're thinking about throughout
whatever piece of work we're
doing whenever we're building
something. How do you actually
do that? How do you actually
design to this more inclusion,
we talked about a bunch of them
already on this call, which is
great. I want to talk about some
of the more general pattern for
how you can get better at
inclusion. And so let's get back
to this idea of rules of pattern
matching. we exclude people
because we internalize rules
that don't accommodate them that
don't include them. So how do we
spot those bad rules? How do we
know that we're doing something
wrong? Particularly if we're not
aware that this is a rule we've
even internalized? This is just
how the world is and exists in
our subconscious. And why we do
this, as we widen our worldview,
we go out and we listen to
people who have different
experiences to us. Because we're
not going to know rule is bad
until we see a counterexample
until we see something that
challenges it. And then we run.
That doesn't feel right. Oh,
that's because I think all x's
are y. But actually, this x is a
Zed. We need to we need to be
able going out and finding lots
of counterexample, finding
people who look different to us,
and listening to their
experiences listening to how
they experienced the world.
Personally, I love Twitter for
this. It's a great medium for
interact, listening to lots of
different people listen to their
worldview. Listen to people who
are different to me. And they
will explain the challenges they
face. And then I register those
numbers are that's a thing I've
never thought about before. And
that affects my view of that
informs my work, you'll do well
and hopefully means the next
time I can find involved with
somebody like them. I'm not
going to do something might be
exclusionary. And certainly not
the only way to do this, you can
find any plenty of mediums let
you talk to people who don't
look like you. That's the one
that works for me. So I actually
know how long I've been going I
have not got overtime. But I
hope that just gives you a
little flavor of why inclusion
samples and for design, why it's
something we have to think about
throughout.
It's not an afterthought. And
hopefully a new framing of
unconscious bias the idea of
spotting patterns that we don't
even realize with we're forming,
and maybe thinking about that as
ways to avoid excluding pieces
in the future. slides and notes
we have the link are at the link
nurse, you can go and get the
Notes and references and so on
from that. And I think that's
probably my turn up.