Unknown: I'm Malika Sharon, I
work as a community manager for
the children way that Kirsty is
the lead for, and I'm also your
oil as team members. The topic
that we're going to discuss
today is called mountain of
engagement. And it is about
discovering pathways and
patterns in engagement in your
work. So first of all, when we
talk about
mountain,
at workspace, this is something
that you all can imagine we have
management level. And within the
organization, each of these
members are leaders with
responsibilities of certain
tasks that are delegated to
them, or that they delegate to
others. And they also are
responsible to finish them. One
does this for them is to create
sense of reward for finishing
certain tasks, but also they
find proportionately, so
appraisals and promotion, that
allows them to gain more
leadership abilities. And we're
going to think about that, in
terms of our members, we will
talk about if these kinds of
mountains can be specifically
adapted within a community of
members, to help them understand
what kind of tasks they like to
engage with, and how we can
offer them recognition for their
work and provide more
opportunities for skill building
and leadership within the
community. This is one of my
most favorite sketches ever,
because we helped design this.
It's because we often talk about
collaboration, when we start
thinking about engagement, and
collaboration and research space
often gets limited to topics
like, what project is this? Who
are we going to work with? What
are our common goal? What are
the resources and skills we
have? And the things that
actually matters? because it
affects all the stakeholders
like, how are we going to teach
the act with them? How are we
going to be providing them an
inclusive workspace? Do we have
Code of Conduct? Are we aiming
to build a diverse team, these
are often not the first thing
that comes in mind when talking
about collaboration. But you
have spent your last month
creating things like Code of
Conduct contribution, guideline,
open licenses, and so on, which
is basically focusing on the
lower part here. So now coming
to the engagement, community
engagement is about giving equal
opportunities to all your
members to exchange values and
empower each other to act on
issues that enhances community
experience and help achieve a
positive outcome. So the focus
is providing the opportunity,
empowering them so that they can
act. Mountain of engagement
helps us discover pathways and
patterns of engagement in our
work. It helps us discover how
people interact with our
community and organization, and
how our cultures get affected by
how do we discover patterns that
help people move from one type
of interaction to other types of
interaction? Can we develop
pathways for them to move from
first contact to sustained
engagement to leadership? So
basically, this picture, again,
where each of these members asks
specific question, if there is a
person who's very new to your
community, and they are aware of
other tasks within the
community, the question could
be, how can I move to the upper
level, there might be some
people who are just there,
because they like your
community, they're probably not
engaging very actively. There
are people who've been there for
a long time, and they want to
gain more leadership skills. And
then there are people who are
there who want to just do the
right task, use the right
resource and use effectively
their time. And then there are
people on the leadership who
might have just started by
fixing a small bug who are now a
regional head. So mounted
mountain of engagement have five
main steps. First is a list of
people's interaction with your
work. Second, is thinking about
deepening levels of engagement.
So in this case, you're going to
create a list of all the
interaction types that exist in
your community. And
independently, you will think
about what are the five levels
of engagement in the leadership
criteria you have. And then
you're going to put them
together as one single grouping
based on the engagement and the
type of interaction that you
have. Moving on. This exact
grouping will allow you to
identify patterns that works and
patterns patterns that do not
work. This could be for example,
what kind of conversation or
interaction platform do I have?
Does it work For everyone, if it
doesn't work do I want to
prioritize or not. So finally,
when you have identified those,
you can prioritize your work to
create more opportunities for
people. So this really helps you
to see what engagement effort in
your community really works. So
the first topic again, people's
interaction, you can think about
Twitter blogging article
mentions, bug report,
pull request, grant application
and hosting local events. So
this in terms of our
communities, also a task that is
done by community members. The
second one is about band of
engagement. So independent of
what kind of engagement
opportunities we have, we can
think about how do people come
in touch with my community?
First? How can they have
sustained relationship with the
community? And how can we
provide leadership? Or you can
even think about, if you're a
community that offers teaching
and learning resources, you can
think about people who come to
learn people who endorse your
community, who participate, who
collaborate, and eventually they
go on to lead? And then
combining them? What is the
first contact? Did they read my
tweet or a blog? to people who
are in the sustained
relationship? Are they
maintaining my resources, people
who are in the leadership
position? Are they taking
ownership of the local events?
And then finally, based on our
third point, we can think about
what are the pattern of
engagement? Who is moving up?
And how, what works for them?
Who gets stuck? Do they feel
frustrated? who leaves? And why
do they leave? Can we repeat the
success and avoid failures? So
these questions to ask when
you're identifying what works
and what doesn't work? What
makes it easy for someone to
move up in your mountain of
engagement? How can we make
those pathway easier for others?
What makes it difficult for
someone to move? And how can we
improve our support? Are there
places where people are happy to
be stuck? Just getting stuck is
not a problem, right? Sometimes
people just want to do something
that they like, they don't want
to particularly move to
leadership positions. So you
need to also think about that,
that you're not forcing people
to leave their band and go to
next level. And then you're
going to prioritize your work to
create more opportunities. At
this point, what's important is
to decide where to put your
effort. Maybe at this point of
time, you want to put your
effort in making your community
more visible. In the next step,
you might want to engage more
with the people who are already
there. And later step you might
want to go on and involve more
people who haven't heard about
your community. And in the, in
those cases, sharing stories are
very important, telling stories
of people who already exist,
what has been successful for
them, what what did not work,
what did you change, you need to
be communicating and things very
transparently. And specifically,
when you're creating an open
project, finally comes down to
reflection. What do you want it
to convey to your community
about how you value delegate and
elevate people in your culture?
So the reflection question could
be what kind of pattern do I see
as people move along the
mountain of engagement? What do
these patterns illustrate about
my community? And how should I
revise my own leadership goal.
So as a leader, open leader,
your role is to create
leadership opportunities for
others within your community. So
you're gonna collect a lot of
data when you're doing this. So
we need to tell you a little bit
about data. We are not lawyer,
and this is not legal advice.
But when you're using, for
example, survey, comply with
GDPR, or something similar that
exists in your country, keep
your data appropriate to your
needs. And don't use it for
different places that you
haven't been in. When you share
your data can your story you
want to tell and never change
the link so that people can come
back to and even track the
history of how you have advanced
in your community. I'm not sure
if GDPR applies to everybody's
work. But in any case, collect
the least amount of data in the
most anonymous way possible.
Share your policy and plan with
the participants early on
storage security, and use it
only as stated and deleted when
you're not using it anymore. And
the big story of this whole
mountain of engagement is to see
what your culture is if you
remember the culture,
conversation we had a few weeks
ago that culture develops. So if
you want to be a part of it or
not as your decision, if you
don't become part of agriculture
can move away from the vision
that you have established for
your community. Your engagement
actually shows what is what you
actually value. It's also
methodology for data collection,
engagement, equity and
storytelling. Because we're
working in a very digital world,
a lot of things can be only told
by data and the progress and
this is a good way to track
that.
So I'm quickly going to move on
to the community interaction
because it closely relates to
mountain of engagement, because
we talk about how are we
interacting with our community
and creating engagement
opportunities with them. So we
will be thinking about these
five things. Are we gifting
something? are we creating
something together? Are we
soliciting ideas? are we
learning through use? Or are we
only networking common interest,
or it could be all five of them
at the same time in your
community? So I will leave a
reference for you to read
afterwards.