Unknown: I'm based in Paris
these days, I'm the director of
research for open humans
foundation here. And I'm based
at the Center for Research and
disciplinarity. Working on
citizen science at large, and
especially on how to use
personal data in citizen
science, but to get started
maybe a bit of what the
different types of citizen
science and I put it in the
scare quotes, because what we
very often see as a citizen
scientist asking people for
their money, which is very
unfortunate, because it makes
the whole idea of actually
contributing to a researcher but
at absurdum, then we have human
computation where humans put in
place for actually analyzing
images or videos, where machine
learning methods or any other
algorithms aren't good enough.
And of course, we have the idea
of using people in crowdsourcing
the data collection itself. And
this background of crowdsourcing
the data collection itself, I
personally started out with when
I started a project where people
donated their genetic data in
the public domain. But a bit of
the issues we see the research
cycle here are the different
stages. And I think, for me,
sharing in the sense of research
also means giving people a way
to share in doing research, and
not just in benefiting from the
outcomes. Unfortunately, having
the citizen science or community
science projects, which are
actually co created the super
rare, there was a survey about
European citizen science
projects last year, and co
created or not even 11% of other
projects. So it's pretty rare.
Most people use regular people
in their research for data
collection, which is
contributory or collaborative,
which has human computation
kinds of citizen science. So
this question of enabling co
creation is especially relevant
when it comes to citizen science
around health and well being
because often, as we discussed
earlier, and the answer is it's
about patient data, or
individuals that have diseases
or have some kinds of problems,
which they want to have softer,
where they actually are experts,
and especially when it comes to
chronic conditions, patients
very often are much more the
experts of their own disease
than any medical professional
could be just because they need
to deal with it. 24 seven
compared to a medical doctor, it
is only on a professional basis.
And my answer for how can we
enable co creation is the idea
of Commons based peer
production, which we see in open
source, which I think many of us
are familiar with even Wikipedia
even more, where the idea is
that it's very non hierarchical,
it's based on negotiated
coordination. So you have a very
flat hierarchy where people
actually need to talk to each
other, and no one can enforce
any rules easily. It's for
benefits or sharing is at the
center of all of it. And to
actually allow people to
participate, it needs to be
modular, small tasks where
people can contribute to based
on their own experience and
skill, which leads to this idea
of producer. So something that
parts of the Commons is
producing can be used to
generate more stuff and
knowledge in the commons at
large. And the question is, how
can we put this in the context
of using personal data for
citizen science and lots of
people are already using
personal data for their own surf
research, as I like to call it
and the quantified self
movement. Lots of people have
wearable devices, everyone uses
Google's social media, maybe
even get their genome analyzed
from 23andme at all. And so I'm
working on this project called
Open humans, which is a way for
using your data for doing
citizen science. And the idea
really, is that what we allow
people to do is aggregate their
data. So if you come to open
humans as an individual, you can
import data from basically all
of the sources I've mentioned,
that can be wearables, Google
searches to is actually one of
the projects which you can
import, if you trust us enough
to store your Google search
history. Mine actually is under
open humans, but it's private,
not public. So you can store all
of this data privately in your
account. And as I said, there's
tons of different sources. So we
have, for example, another thing
that actually patients will just
importing glucose monitoring
data and the Type One Diabetes
community everyone, there's
varying continuous glucose
monitors. So people import real
time 24, seven data of their
glucose levels, which they then
want to use for research
purposes. And once you've done
this, you can actually start on
an individual level to do
citizen science on the end of
one just by yourself if you want
for this in open humans, we have
this little trip perhaps set up
where you can read data analysis
notebooks, which you can share
with others. So we have this
public collection of lots of
different data analysis tools,
which use different data
sources, and you can just look
at them. And if you click on any
of them, you can open up and run
this analysis using your
personal data because the data
is centralized in open human so
you can just reuse notebooks and
reproduce analysis on your own
data instead of using mine, for
example. And just to give a few
examples of this one, but it's a
funny one, which uses
productivity tracking data,
which I
have collected over the years
along with my variable device
data. And what you can see on
the right is this very strong
correlation between how many
hours I spent on the Xbox In
front of my computer using my
computer, compared to how much
physical activity I get it 2017
is the year I was writing my PhD
thesis. So you see lots and lots
of our players were spent long
hours in the office writing my
PhD, but I didn't do any
physical activity. And you could
even correlate this as well with
my smartscape to see how my wage
increase because I was just
working and not doing anything
else. And we just mentioned
earlier, the whole issue about
the current situation, we just
had a community called Open
humans, I think yesterday, and
started this little quantified
flu project to see whether we
can use wearable device data to
predict when someone might fall
just based on the physiological
signals like heart rate, body
temperature, and so on before
they exhibit any conscious
symptoms. And we made like an
output for this today, actually,
which is here, for two incidents
where a person was sick, which
is the red vertical line, which
tells you that they actually
transect and on the y axis you
have the body temperature. And
you see even like a bit before
people notice that actually know
that gets sick that there's
already an increase in the body
temperature, which you can use
in the data people already
routinely collect on stuffs in
any case. And we are expanding
on this idea a bit right now
with this King's Memorial on
self research, Stephen Keating
passed away I think, a bit less
than a year ago from a brain
tumor. And he was a member of
our board with the open humans
foundation. And he was the
biggest data share about
personal data. He got his cancer
genome sequences, regular genome
sequence, he got 3d models of
this brain tumor get like a 15
hour video of his own life awake
brain surgery, because you need
to stay awake. So they know when
they have removed for attaching
benefits, you actually should
keep in mind sort of just
removing humor. And he released
all of this data publicly and
said, Please use my data and
somehow to research on this. And
inspired from this, we are now
doing a project where we have I
think around 80 people enrolled
to do individual research
projects around their own
interests. And we have different
patient groups, we have people
who have no disease at all,
they're just interested in
learning about themselves. And
it's inspiring people to do
research by themselves. But the
more interesting part, of
course, for many of us here, I
think is the part where you
share data with academic or
community driven projects for
use in citizen science. And for
these also, there's lots of lots
of projects here already have
some are led by academics like
the keeping pace, one at NYU,
about using wearable devices to
understand seasonal patterns and
physical activity. We also have
some which are led by patient
communities, which I think I
don't see it on the slide up to
the right, the nightscout Data
Commons is like a patient group
of type one diabetes patients
and they are collecting all the
data, they're already feeding
into the system to do their own
research projects to understand
how they can optimize, for
example, their insulin usage,
which diet helps them to
minimize insulin use, especially
in countries like the US where
it's prohibitively expensive to
use insulin. And just to give
one very concrete example, this
is the patient driven research
project around cluster headaches
called no bism. But started by a
couple of cluster headache
patients in the Netherlands, and
cluster headaches. It's like the
worst form of migraines, which
are also called switch side
headaches, because people
actually end up killing
themselves just like their
headache attack stuff. So it's
really terrible. It's not really
even rare. It's about as rare as
multiple sclerosis, but they
only get around 1% of the
research funding compared to
multiple sclerosis. So there's
very little academic research by
being rather common. So they
started making their own
application for collecting data
on when do they have their text,
what might be potential
triggers? And what interventions
are they doing. The example here
on the screenshot is microdosing
magic mushrooms, because many of
them are in the Netherlands. And
you can get magic magic
mushrooms illegally. And so they
collect this data, individually
the storage and open Yuan sister
data store and then share the
state of for example, what they
are doing is they collaborate
with the Code Academy because
the patients themselves don't
have the expertise in analyzing
the data. So they reached out to
data science students at this
Code Academy to actually get the
students to learn data science
on real world actual data. And
in return, they get back the
university students do which
they otherwise would not be able
to do. And in return the status
also use them for donating to
advocacy and outreach purposes,
for example. So the last thing,
of course, doing this is it's a
matter of governance. So how can
you build trust of your
participants into a citizen
science and how can you build a
community and what we've tried
to do is be very open about all
parts of hardware. So we are
completely open source.
Everything is visible to
everyone except for the personal
data. But this includes the
governance as well. So the first
thing we are doing is every
single project you want to run
an open Humans, you need to ask
for permission from the
community to actually set up
Life. And here's an example of a
interesting study that one
individual did. She was doing
this a psycho, fun research
project. And she wants to study
whether there's any genetic
associations to Myers Briggs
personality types. So she posted
like, I have this project I
would like, like to run it on
open humans on the forum, which
then contains all the
description and she even got IRB
approval. So she gave
documentation for this as well
and everything. But then the
community was kind of split.
Some people were like, yep,
let's IRB approved, it's
completely fine. We should allow
this project to run and someone
else was like, are you basically
crazy, this is pretty much like
pop psychology doing Myers
Briggs, and there will be
nothing out there that's
actually useful that we can
learn from using this data. And
the community talked for, for
quite a bit about this to figure
out how to solve it. And in the
end to agree that open humans
has infrastructure, because
there's no harm in taking your
personality test, and that you
will never get any jeebus
results, it's fine to run it.
But the community discusses and
actually discusses with the
person running the project to
figure out what the consensus
might be and without consensus
projects can launch. The second
bit of governance is that open
humans run by a nonprofit
foundation based in the US. And
our borders are actually at
least 1/3 elected directly from
every member. So if you go to
the open humans website, and you
click an account, you are now
eligible to vote in the next
board election and decide who is
even officially in charge of
running the foundation on your
behalf. And the community
members can nominate themselves
to run the service will actually
start I think next week, because
we have three open board seats
coming up. So we will have
people in nominating themselves
and then voting just online for
their favorite candidates. So to
set up so citizen science in our
case really means allowing
people to use their own data and
making informed decision of how
to use this data. And I think
it's going back to the questions
we had earlier. It's like
informed consent. We are trying
to do the sort of citizen
science setting more than in the
academic research setting, we're
actually people are in both
making all the decisions and not
just signing a consent form at
the end. And this allows both
academic and patient projects to
run. And what's really important
in citizen sciences make people
play an active role in the
governance as much as you can,
and this is of interest. We have
an open select which you can
join