Unknown: First thing we're going
to be talking about is agile and
iterative project management.
And it helps if I'm on the first
slide rather than this last one.
Let's make that big. Okay, can
you still see? Guys screen? Yay,
fantastic, right? Okay, so we're
just going to talk a bit about
some iterative, project
management's for your project.
So project management workflows
for your project, including ways
to automate that I'm going to
talk a little bit about agile,
but we're not going to touch on
it a whole lot when we're going
to take from the spirit of Agile
Project methodology, then
actually teaching it because
agile itself, and people tend to
pay for days or weeks worth of
courses for agile or project
management. So this is me, you
may have met me before, I'm
fairly mostly live sales. And I,
like I mentioned, I'll be
talking about agile. So that's
actually got a sticky note
background. Because anyone who
has ever worked in a physical
Agile Software team will
probably be familiar, there are
post it notes everywhere, it's a
bit like the carpentries. So
what is agile beyond a word in
English, that means nimble. So
it started in 2001. As a bunch
of people getting together, they
all worked for corporate
software houses. And they were a
bit frustrated with some of the
ways that things were working.
And they wrote a short manifesto
about ways that they wanted
things to get better. I'm not
going to read all of this,
because some of this is very
corporate and software. So most
of us don't necessarily have
customers. And many of our
projects may not be software.
But if you look in the middle of
the big words, individuals and
interactions over processes and
tools was one of their core
values. Another core value, I'll
skip to the bottom of the large
text ones is responding to
change over following a plan.
And perhaps the moral of the
story that I'm trying to get to
here is what they were favoring
world's flexibility and talking
to people and interacting with
people over a really strict rule
bound, project management styles
and behaviors. Or to explain a
bit more what they were pushing
back against when addre was
founded. On the left here, we
have the waterfall methodology,
which is when someone is
designing a software project,
one way that you could do this
as you gather requirements, and
then you move on to designing
based on those requirements. you
implement those requirements.
And then you verify that the
thing that you have implemented
works as according to the
requirements in the original
step. One, one flaw with this is
that you're usually verifying
that it works based on the
requirements and not necessarily
based on what the customer
wants. And it's called waterfall
because it's very rigid, and you
flow from one step and down to
the next step, and you can't go
back. So if this was over a
three year timeline, you might
spend the first six months
gathering requirements, two
years designing and
implementing. And then the final
bit verifying and maintaining.
And part of the problem with
this project. Project Management
management methodology is that
if you didn't do anything,
right, any point like you
misunderstood the requirements,
you couldn't go back, there
wasn't time left in the
schedules and the behaviors. And
it meant that sometimes the
thing that produced was very
much to specifications, but not
necessarily what anyone really
wanted. And so agile pushes back
against that and says we need to
be interacting with people all
the time, we need to be doing
things in small chunks, and it
needs to be iterative. So that's
what the right hand diagram is
here. So if you look at the gray
cubes, we have a backlog, these
are items that are things that
need to be done. And you take
off a small discrete chunk, at
any given time you work on that
task, it might be a day or a
week, or a month worth of tasks.
But once that's done, you then
release it. And the idea is that
at any given time, what you're
releasing is actually a complete
project with just a little bit
more on each time. And then you
also you get feedback from the
people you're working with,
whether that be a customer or an
anon software scenario, it's
more likely to be perhaps your
community or your peers. And
then you pull that back. And so
when you've had feedback, you
you'll end up adding more items
to your backlog. And so it's a
much more circular cycle. And it
means that releases are shorter,
smaller, but they tend to be
what people want, which tends to
work much more nicely.
I just send this up again. So
whilst This was originally a
software development
methodology, it's also really,
really good for project
management in general. And the
idea is you break your work up
into really small chunks, rather
than having a really fixed long
timeline. And I think given that
many people in academia may be
working on short term grants for
the year or three years. And,
again, you can see why perhaps
having something attractive that
you're constantly checking
whether or not you was what you
want over a certain timescale.
It's It's logical to work
iteratively as well in scenarios
where we may be working. So
how might I want
to use this in my project, you
say, so I was really proud of
this little image I found where
it has a big challenge the big
egg full of smaller eggs, just
going for the idea that we have
a large, a large milestone of
some sort, but then you break it
down into the smaller chunks and
the smaller tasks that you might
want to work on. So in this
case, we're calling a large
chunk and milestone, so some
main large goal that you might
be wanting to work on, pick that
milestone and start to break it
down into tiny tasks. And I
would suggest try and get those
tasks to be between one or two
hours to no more than a day or
two. If it's going to be taking
more than a day or two, there's
a good chance that you can't
estimate how long it's really
going to take because it's
comprised of so many different
things that you might be
forgetting some. And that it's
always better to break it down
into smaller tasks until you can
estimate easily how long they're
going to be. So I have a couple
of real world examples of
existing projects broken down
into nice, small tasks. So this
is a project board on GitHub,
that has broken down into
releases. It's a roadmap,
basically, and this is where I
work by the way into mine. And
so it's a biological data
warehouse, which is kind of
irrelevant at this point. But
what I did want to show was that
on the left, we have intimated
4.1 point two, this was the
release plan that we have we
said in January, and you have a
set of tasks. And you can see
each of the tasks actually is
complete, because you can see
the little exclamation mark with
a check mark on the left. And
that one was actually already
been released, which is why all
those tasks are complete. Then
the next one, we have it for
point 1.3. In the next column,
we have some tasks that we think
we're going to release in
February. And as we get further
into future things, get the Vega
and Vega. So into my 4.2 point,
oh, we say spring 2019. This is
a very northern hemisphere
centric, I do apologize. But
again, we're no longer at the
point of months, because we know
that this is bigger, it's harder
for us to estimate because it's
further away. And the final
column on the right, which is
kind of cut off into Mountain
5.0. So far in the future, we
haven't broken it down into many
tasks, and we haven't estimated
when it will be yet. So the
closer something is, the more
granular it should be
effectively. Or here is a
another example. This is the
binder hub for the cheering way.
And one thing I think is really
nice. And this one is that
rather than having the releases
like we had on the previous one
for into mine, we actually have
a set of there's a flow where
tasks can run through. So on the
left, you have tasks that
haven't been done yet and your
to do in the middle, you have
ones that we're currently
working on. And then on the
right, we have tasks that are
already done. And what's really
nifty is that GitHub will
actually take pay attention to
the actions that you're taking
in these tasks, and it will
automatically move them through
the board. So tasks that are in
to do that you begin to work on
will automatically move into in
progress. And when you close a
task, it'll automatically hop
over into done. So it means that
you have a really nice
transparent roadmap for anyone
that they can see what you're
working on. But it's actually
not that much admin work,
because a lot of it is automated
as a nice, sufficient and easy
workflow. And then I've tried to
create an example that is a bit
more hands on to something that
everyone can maybe relate to, if
you have a relatively young
project, then you might be
thinking about a milestone for
you might be how to prepare a
website for my project. And so
I've broken that down into two
possible tasks. One would be
domain names, I want to get a
domain name for my project. On
the right hand, I have to create
the content for my website. And
then since those are also kind
of vague, I break those down
further. So domain names, I say,
let's agree on a domain name
with my team members, purchase
that domain name and then set it
up on GitHub. Since we'll be
using GitHub to host your
website. Oops, I went too far.
And on the right, I've broken it
down into ways to create content
for my website. And then in
scenarios where the task was too
vague, like right in about page,
I've also broken it down
together by those emails,
pictures. And so each time when
the task looks larger, break it
down into a smaller size.
And then I've also set up a demo
project board on GitHub so that
you can actually see some of the
automation. So can you see my
GitHub screen as it's done
slides? configure help.
Fantastic. Okay, so these are
the same tasks that I had shown
in the slides. And I close this
task earlier, I said, we've
already agreed on a domain name.
We can click on that. You see,
we've got let's use open ai.org
for our website. We agreed on
that. When I closed it, it
automatically got merged into
the done column. So let's say
there now I have actually just
purchased it, and I think Well,
that seems good. I'm going to
close it now so that I can just
go To move this the other way,
okay, yes, I'm going to close
this issue since we've now
purchased a domain name. So I've
clicked on it, I'm gonna say, I
purchased this. And now when I
close and comment, if I go back
to the board, you can see that
that has automatically moves to
the done column. So it becomes
very effective and easy way to
actually automate some of the
task workflows that you've been
working on when it's broken down
very efficiently and cleanly
like this. And the other thing,
I will show two more things. One
is if you add tasks, you can
create issues on GitHub, like
normal. So these are just normal
GitHub issues. So if I go to my
issues, here, you can see, these
are all my issues. And these
are, for example, convert buyers
to markdown. It's exactly the
same one is in here, and further
down. Oh, no, it's not there.
Haha. Okay, it can be. So I've
clicked add cards in the top
right. And I can literally just
drag that in and say that still
to do. And you can also drag
cards between these columns
manually if for some reason that
you feel like that's necessary
as well. And you can also see
here, there's a tracking bar up
on the top left with the purple
and the green gives us an idea
which which how many tasks are
done, how many are in progress,
and how many are still to do. So
it's a nice effective way to
actually manage your projects in
a public and efficient way. And
that's as much of a demo with
our ad. Now, I know, I'll add
one more thing. So if something
for some reason, you don't want
to make an issue, let's say it's
it's not formal enough, or it's
not defined enough to make an
issue, clearly, you can just add
quick to do notes here. So let's
say I want to add a contact, I'm
typing it wrong. There we go add
a contact page. And that's just
using the class on the top
right, adding a note. So you can
see that is slightly different
from the others. Where is it
gone? There we go. So that's not
actually an issue. But that
means it doesn't appear on the
issues if for some reason, I
don't want it to but then if I
wanted to convert it to an
issue, I could do so as well.
Now it will appear here, so
should be seven in the issues
now. Yeah. So it's a nice way to
manage your tasks. So that's all
I'll go into for this. But at
the minute, if any of that
interested you. I haven't
touched all that much on agile
methodologies. But there are a
lot of different things that you
can learn. So one agile
methodology is Scrum. And this
has a lot of ceremonies and a
lot of formality, which seems
ironic given that, actually
agile talked a lot about not not
having processes. Extreme
Programming is another agile
methodology, Ken Ben is actually
the methodology where he served
those boards, the project was
removing things from to do to
Dan and so on. That is actually
the campaign methodology. But
you can read more about that as
well. We also have a link to
interactive interacts or
iterative interaction design. So
UX user experience design tends
to use a similar iterative
looping back process. So if you
care about how people enjoy
working on your project, it's
definitely worth a bit of a read
of that. I've added a few bits
of the Agile glossary, some of
their jargon that use there's a
lot of jargon and in Agile, I
could probably have five or six
slides comfortably just covering
that, but those are some of the
ones that you're most likely to
encounter. And Thoreau, Harriet,
who's also a software
Sustainability Institute fellow
has an interesting projects to
get more agile into academia. So
there's an interesting blog post
you shared here. And finally, we
have some more notes about
GitHub project automation, if
that's of interest to anyone,
so