Unknown: I will talk now about
road mapping for open project.
And that's wrong one. So what we
will do is what we will see how
we can use a road map to plan
your walk in contribution for a
project for your project for
your project, and look at some
examples, and do during at the
end of the course, we will give
you an assignment to create or
revise your, your roadmap for
your project. But I will first
introduce you to the roadmap.
So, same as you mentioned, so,
it's the same introduction to
open EDA design and build
project that empower others to
collaborate. And I will talk a
bit now about the collaboration
part and our the roadmap can
help you to empower others to
collaborate within inclusive
communities to your project.
Again, with nice tables of
designing, building and pouring
and for understanding sharing
and participation. And now with
the roadmap will focus on this
the part on the top right,
participation and inclusion. So
how you design your project to
add participation and
inclusions. So the idea is to to
develop a welcoming space that
make a good first impression
that you you are new
contributors are in the right
place to contribute that they
feel welcome. And that they can
be they can get involved in one
project. But for that you let
you need to let them know what's
going on what's happening, what,
what is the current status of a
project, what you what you as a
leader of a project, you want to
what is your vision, so you
already write your visions, that
you can detail it a bit more
with the roadmap. And so a
roadmap will be a summary of a
project welcoming people to
contribute welcoming people, and
how they can get involved. And
usually you have a timeline. So
it's a three main main parts in
the roadmap, these three parts.
The first part of the project
summary and welcome will make
people we are welcome people
orient people to your to your
project. So usually there has
been linked to your map
directly. So they never maybe
never heard about your project.
They they went directly to your
roadmap. So it's important to
end them understanding where
they are, what is your project?
What is it about what is your
visions, and that they
understand their vision, their
the big idea about the project.
And to give them a clear focus,
it also helps you to give a
focus when writing the rest of
the roadmap, if you already
wrote write the visions. So the
project summary first is the
first thing that you will have
in your roadmap. And then the
second step is out to get
involved. So some new
contributors may want to just
jump right away, they want to
contribute directly. But though,
then you need to point them were
out to some documentations to
how they can contribute. Maybe
you have some easy to contribute
issues or something, it's
important to do that in your in
your in your roadmap, you will
need to do that too, to tell
them how they can get involved.
and point them to important part
two, the different part of your
project. The third part and the
more the more important part of
your roadmap will be the
timeline. So you need to
organize tasks to complete your
project around different
milestones and that it will map
what you are working on and what
is going next. So what is your
currently tasks that you need to
achieve what end what is your
visions, maybe on short term,
meters and long term. And so you
define different milestones that
can be turning point a
significant turning point or
event that we move your your
project for what it can be
statues. So for example, you
have a feature release plan, you
have a minimal, minimal viable
product that you want to
release. It can be also an
event. So for example, you
organize a hackathon and you
have different milestones you
want to achieve these things
before the hackathon or during
the hackathon or you have a
deadline for submission of a
paper somewhere or for
conference for example, and you
want to achieve things before it
can be sorts of timeframe. So as
I mentioned, oh, there is a
mistakes. And beside the
timeframe, the short time is a
short term, medium term and long
terms.
frame for your project. So it's
important to when you write
your, you're going to have to
pick 123 milestones for your
timeline. And then once you have
them, you can list some tasks to
complete for each of the
milestones that will include
information to make to help
people to contribute to know
what has to be done, what will
be successful, what will be a
successful fifth tasks out
should look like how you can get
started. So maybe point to some
documentation or some part of
your code to say, Okay, how can
I do that, and why this task is
important. So on finalize that
to make sure that you relate
that to your vision. And the
question is how you can share
now this will map how you store
your roadmap. And we were
discussing quickly with my
weekend, you're in the beginning
of the course. And that's, and
it's moving quite short, it's
changing a lot. So the way you
can do it is before I will say,
until recently, it was you have
a separate file called
roadmap.md. And if you go to
this link, they're open
discovery. I don't know if I
can, Oh, do you see my screen?
If I open it? Nope. Still your
slides. Okay, sorry. So you can
go through the links later. But
you can store in a roadmap find
attendee for Zeppelin, if you
have a GitHub repository, where
you storing this remap, then
that people can find later, you
can also put that in the readme
file. But I must admit that I
didn't find a good example,
recent example up to date
example of a readme file with a
roadmap inside, because
nowadays, I would say most of
the people use an issue. So you
have an issue too, with a
roadmap, for example, for the
open life science applications.
So I think it was Yeah, when we
saw in for the last trimester.
So we have this roadmap, what we
need to do for the applications
for our program here. And we
wrote a roadmap for that. But
also, if you're using GitHub to
for your project, you have this
nice project tabs in GitHub. And
that is you can see in the top
of your of the project, which is
really nice to organize your
roadmap there. For example, the
galaxy project, they use that
and it's quite powerful, because
you can really move things
forward. In the end, it's
totally open so people can see
it. But then you need to be sure
that your vision and things are
clear before and I was it was
just a global overview of what
is a roadmap, I will recommend
you to go through the different
the different examples that I
show you because they are
they're quite okay. quite nice.
And and to try to draft your
roadmap for your project. It
doesn't have to be a final one.
It's just a first version of
your offshore roadmap. And it
will help you to know what you
want to do and which steps you
want to achieve. And also the
timing for that. And yeah, when
coming new contributors, and on
that, I would like to thank you
for listening for that. And to
that. And yeah, again, sharing
the same idea of our programs
and Yep, thank you.