Unknown: So I'm going to talk
about, I guess, the rise in open
software, in academic research
that's really sort of
transformed how we do research
has done so over the last few
years. So let's just sort of
start by asking why why would we
want to use and promote open
source software in the first
place. And I guess, partly its
response to the so called
reproducibility replication
crisis in the biomedical
sciences for over the last
decade or so, there's been an
increasing realization that much
of the published literature
findings can't actually be
replicated by other people. And
that's caused a lot of problems,
particularly in psychology,
which is my area. And in a
sense, recognizing that there's
a crisis in terms of
reproducibility. And
replication, has encouraged
people to go out there and look
at various tools, and new ways
of doing research so that they
can adopt them and actually
reduce the chances of these
reproducibility problems
occurring in the future. And as
an academic, I've seen huge
changes over the last, you know,
four or five years alone, and I
saw this really nice tweet, but
six months or so ago from
somebody who attended one of the
brain hacks summer schools, who,
you know, was it a great
research lab, which, you know,
is kind of doing research, I
guess, along the lines of how
they've always done research. In
parallel to the kind of the
traditional way of doing
research, there's been this
explosion and the adoption of
open computational tools, such
as coding languages, such as
Python, and R. binder. And the
world and academia is kind of
splitting ensues, people are
still stuck in their kind of
closed systems way of doing
things. And those younger
academics are kind of really
embracing the full range of
computational tools that are
available to them. And I guess
this is partly in response to a
lot of work that people like
brand new sec, engaged with when
he and colleagues established
the Center for Open Science,
which puts it at center has
mentioned, the idea that we need
to be transparent in our
research practices. And if we're
transparent in our research
practices, if we use software
that other people can reuse,
we're going to do a lot better
in terms of populating the
academic literature with journal
articles are likely to be
reporting correct results rather
than false positives. The Center
for Science has had a huge role
in terms of advocating the
adoption of open research
practices. They were involved in
developing the transparency and
openness promotion guidelines,
which over 5000 academic
academic journals of my life
signed up to, which kind of
highlights the need for openness
at all stages of the research
cycle, including, importantly,
at the level of the schools in
requiring, and verifying shared
code that's used in the analysis
behind journal articles, always
like this. visualization
developed by Roger Pang, which
really highlights the full range
of steps in the research cycles
require reproducibility, where
ultimately link in your
software, your data, and your
competition environment is the
gold standard in terms of spin
gauging and freely reproducible
work. One of the risks of using
close code, these are clear
examples you might have come
across previously is that very
often things can happen to your
data, because of the way the
closed code is working, that can
fundamentally make your results
non reproducible if there was a
case a few years ago with
Microsoft Excel, which was
automatically converting the
some genes to the UPS,
misidentified them as calendar
dates, and ended up producing
our kind of garbled, you know,
files that really, really lost
important information because of
this.
Similarly, few years ago, and
the height of the global
financial crisis, the US
government, and a number of
other governments, including the
British government decided to
implement austerity. And this
was partly as a function of work
that economists had carried out,
showing that austerity wasn't
necessarily going to cause
growth problems in the world.
And a student was actually given
as homework, the challenge of
recreating these findings and he
couldn't So he emailed the
economists who are working on
this project and asked them for
their data and code, he found
out that during due to coding
errors, and Excel, they had
actually excluded some really
important subsets of the data,
which if they hadn't played, it
wouldn't have led them through
adopting the same conclusion
that they had done. So the risks
behind closed code, whereas open
code and software that loads for
transparency in terms of what
you're doing in terms of your
data processing pipeline, in
terms of your modeling,
pipeline, etc. but crucially, it
also allows others to be able to
spot mistakes that might be
cropping up. A few months ago,
there was this nice article in
Ars Technica, which highlighted
an issue with some competition
software and chemistry, which
actually works slightly
differently depending on the
operating system that the script
was running in. And it has to do
with the way in which files were
ordered. And there have been a
number of papers published,
that, you know, had produced,
you know, arguably, less than
perfect results on the basis of
this problem. But because all
the code was open, it meant that
somebody could spot it, somebody
could craft it. And that problem
won't persist in future, it's
not really focused on the fact
that, you know, when you're
engaged in using other people's
open source software, creating
your own, you're actually
engaged with community, which I
think something that's very
important, there are more eyes
than yours on your DSL on code
when you could learn the open
rates. In my own area of
psycholinguistics. The mixed
models approach developed
primarily for research and
psychology and ecology has
really had a massive influence
over the last few years, with
the guilty package for mixed
models analysis in our being the
element four package. And what's
nice about this example is that
the elemi four package is
updated on a very regular basis
to reflect the latest
developments in statistical
research and statistical
modeling. So the kind of
packages for doing your
analysis, published in an open
way, allow other researchers to
update them and to contribute.
So that means when you're
building your statistical
models, you really are using the
latest knowledge the
statisticians have about these
kind of, sort of model
constructions, or so for using
proxy software such as SPSS, you
really using models were
developed probably quite a few
years ago, and you're never
quite sure under the hood, what
algorithms actually work in
what's going on when the data
when the results of the analysis
are being generated. We can also
make our workflows open as well
using, you know, our standard
workflow approach, which again,
allows and encourages others to
look at the various stages of
your workflow, to kind of
contribute to your code, and to
help make it better. Ultimately,
we want to publish our software
and code we're working on
ourselves. There are a number of
really nice ways in which we can
do that, which up to a few years
ago, just wasn't possible
because traditional discipline
specific journals rarely
published, open source software.
So the journals, journals, open
research software and journal is
open source software are both
great, because they're very
developer friendly journals that
make sure that the software that
you're publishing has had expert
eyes looking at, you've got,
it's been properly tested, and
whatnot. So when it goes out
there in the world, it's kind of
got, you know, a good sort of
BSS behind in terms of a set of
set of reviews. Going to just
mention binder very, very
briefly, I know kind of running
out of time, binders, a really
nice way of actually doing the
Roger Pang sort of gold
standard, reproducible research
by bundling your data, your
code, under competition
environments, all together to
allow others to basically run
your analysis
on the date that you actually
carried the date, there's a link
here to a nice talk by jj
allaire from the RCD conference
a few weeks ago, which I think
you might find interesting to
watch later. Finally, it's
really important to make your
software if you're developing
software, include yourself to
make it suitable. And you can do
that probably most easily with
sudo. And GitHub, as the noodle
aligns your GitHub repository to
get a DUI. And if it's got a DUI
at sizable by others, it can
also be picked up by Google
Scholar. figshare is another
option as well, where you can
actually have different releases
on GitHub, kind of captured
within within figshare. It's
really important when you're
using other people's open source
software that he cited, it's
important for reproducibility
reasons you need to know. You
need to tell people what
versions of different packages
you were using, do your
analysis, there been some
changes in the context of our
and the way that some of the
sample functions worked, which
means that our 3.6 doesn't work
in the same way that are 3.5 or
3.4. That because of the
randomization procedures, and
ultimately, you would never use
somebody else's research
findings without citing the
paper, which defines the code.
So obviously, we wouldn't want
to be reusing somebody else's
software without citing it to.
For better and worse,
researchers. RFCs are often
measured in academia by their
search Association count. So we
need to recognize the software
that people are developing as
well. And finally, I just wanted
to finish by giving a bit of a
sort of shout out to the
cheering way, which was a
phenomenal handbook and lots of
people sort of in this call have
been involved in it. And that's
a good handbook covering
covering the full range of
reproducibility. Not just open
software, but open data and
everything else.