Unknown: So here we are at,
these are three of us. So I'll
actually ask Bernice and yield
to introduce themselves. And
then I'll go ahead.
And Berenice was talking for in
Germany. And I'm happy to be
there and to have you in this
program. Yo,
Hey, everyone. So I'm yo yahudi.
I am a software engineer in
Cambridge, and I am really,
really excited to be working
with you all, for the next few
months.
Hey, so I am Malik Asher, and
I'm a community manager. This
until this week in Germany, but
I'm moving to London next week.
And I'm also super excited to
work on this. So again, three of
us have worked for several
months with really, really
generous people in our mentor
and expert group. And we're
really excited that we're
finally in a stage where we can
welcome you into the program.
The idea that connected us was
that we believe that our to be
effective science should be
shared openly with others and
made freely available. And you
are here with us. And you're
here because in some ways, you
also believe in the same idea.
The open Life Science Program
helps early stage researchers
and potential academic leaders
in becoming Open Science
ambassadors. And I assume that
you all had read something about
it before you apply for the
program. And we are happy that
you are willing to become that
ambassador in your community. So
it's it's something that we know
for decades, from probably from
the beginning of science that it
can advance only when we share
our work with others because
other people can build on what
you have done. And you can work
on someone else's work. But
often, we hear that researchers
are skeptical to be open about
their work, they don't want to
share it because they have fear
of getting scooped being openly
criticize. Or or other people
can spot mistakes in their own
work. So how can we work openly
without becoming scientifically
vulnerable? It's a really
complex question. The
vulnerability is quite different
for different people. And what
we are trying to do is in this
program, we want to explore what
are the important concepts and
practices in open science that
we can apply in our work one
step at a time without
overwhelming others. So life
science is a 15 week long
personal mentorship and cohort
based training, you would have
cold based calls like this one
every second week, and in
between, you will have one on
one mentoring call with your
mentor. And when you're not
talking to either of us, you're
going to have some hands on
practices will provide you with
assignments and after you have
gone through assignment, you
will be introduced to an idea
and concept which you will be
able to apply directly in your
project. So we will be using
Mozilla open leadership
framework which you can access
online openly to feel our open
life science journey. So this,
the whole idea of open
leadership is that open leader
design, build and empower their
projects and communities for
understanding sharing and
participation and inclusion. So
our open science definition goes
beyond just sharing data, but
it's also about bringing people
in. So you can do science
together. The open leadership
framework depends on design,
build and empower principle in
terms of understanding, sharing
and participation. For example,
are we designing our content for
someone else's understanding our
building it for people to share
in their network? Are we
empowering people for their
participation and inclusion in
our community? Can we inspire
their contribution? How can we
help people to take care of
themselves? How can we build
resilience? So our science is
not just about what we produce,
but people who are doing it? So
often, we get asked, What do we
know about what we think about
open science because everyone's
open science is quite different.
Open Science may mean quite
different things to different
people. So it could mean that
you want to share your data
openly, or you want to share
your code openly. You want to
design hardware or you want to
share your paper protocols. You
want to also start sharing your
results from early on before
even it goes into printing. And
then we also have huge focus on
knowledge sharing and training
and collaborating with people
openly like citizen science that
a lot of you are interested in,
but also connecting others in
our field and supporting them in
scientific networks. So what we
want to focus on from the
beginning is the design
thinking, how can we make our
project open by design 2012
studies showed that companies
that have level of strategic
intent to openness and not just
openness alone, so here the
intention is important. it
correlates with the market
performance. So design openness
into a work Don't let it be a
thoughtless default.
So with that, we believe that
you're already leaders in your
own community and you will come
with a vision and if you're
going to combine it with what we
are trying to provide through
our open Life Science program,
you can definitely achieve
positive cultural change in your
community.