Unknown: I'm very excited to be
here and talk a little bit about
open protocols. My name is Anita
potlucks, and I'm the head of
outreach at protocols that I O.
And I would like to start
actually with a little story.
And this is the story of Rocky
to scientist recruited here. And
he's very excited to have his
first day in a new lab. And he's
ready to plan this first
experiment. But because this is
something that he's never worked
with before, he needs to figure
out what he needs to do for his
first experiment. So he decides
to look at the lab notebook from
the previous post stock, but
unfortunately, turns out that
lab notebook is a paper lab
notebook. And nobody really
knows where it is. And it's
lost. So maybe the previous
poster took it with him or her
or it's somewhere but nobody
knows where it is. So he cannot
look at the lab notebook. So he
decides, oh, well, let me check
the papers. So he starts reading
publications, and he thinks he
will find the method description
in the publication. And the
publication says we did
reference 45 did. So he goes to
reference 45 publication that
says, we did put other stuff and
that publication. And he's like,
well, how did the others do it.
And then original publication
says, we did this with
conventional methods. And of
course, this is very
exaggerated. But not only rocky
has this problem. But
oftentimes, it's actually very,
very hard to repeat or build
upon previously published work.
And one of the reasons is often
the lack of detailed recipes
describing how the research and
experiments were performed. So I
think scientists can be really
better at describing what they
expect, what they actually did
for the experiments to make it
easier for others to reproduce
the work. And our mission and
protocols that I use to make it
easy for others to share method
details before, during and after
publication. Um, so protocols
that IO is an open access
repository for methods, we do
have about 6000 protocols on the
platform right now. And they are
on a large diversity of
disciplines. So we don't try to
limit ourselves to one specific
research field, we do welcome
all kinds of research protocols.
And yeah, all the methods are
open access, you don't need to
create an account or anything to
view the public content, you can
just come to the side search for
things and you'll see all the
public methods for that search
keywords that you're entering.
And the special thing about the
methods on protocols that I use
is that they're interactive and
dynamic protocols. So the
protocols are not static PDFs,
but they're interactive and
dynamic. And a couple of things
I want to highlight here. So
this is what the typical
protocols look like. So one,
you'll notice that every public
protocol gets a DUI. So it's
like a pool, you can include it
in your manuscript when you
publishing it, you can include
it in your sheet or submissive
section. And then another thing
is that we have a commenting
functionality. so others can
leave comments on your protocol,
unlike a protocol level, or also
on the step level. So if there's
like a specific step of your
protocol that was unclear or
maybe needed further
explanation, they can leave a
comment on a specific step. And
then the author and everybody
who's following this protocol
will get a notification about
any comment. And then the
discussion happens right there
under protocol. And then we also
want to so you can see here,
this one is actually version two
protocols. So we really want to
make it easy to always share
corrections and optimizations of
protocols. So if you publish a
protocol, and you keep working
on that method, with literally a
click of a button, you can click
new version, and you can create
a new version of your method.
And then everybody who's using
this method will be always
guided to the newest version. So
they'll get like a little pop up
that says there's a new version
of those protocols available,
would you like to see the
original version or the new
version, and then we also do
preserve all the older version.
So you can always go back and
see what changed between the
different versions. But we do
want to make it easy to update
protocols. And then also, the
protocols are entered in like an
easy to follow step by step
description. So you don't have
like a long hard to understand
text block. We do encourage
everybody to encourage step by
step in a step by step format.
And we also do have like a run
button on every protocol. So
when you're in the lab, ready to
follow protocol, you can use
this rattling functionality to
actually track your experiments,
you can check off every single
step, as you complete it,
everything gets the timestamp.
And then we have like an
electronic lab notebook record
kind of thing at the end of the
experiment run.
Yeah, to create a protocol on
protocols that IO, you do need
to create an account for that.
So for that you need to create
an account. But it's really
easy, you basically just click
new protocol and that brings it
to our critical editor. And in
the protocol editor has a bunch
of like regular text editing
tools, but we also do have like
all these components that you
can see on the on the right hand
side here that allows you to
just add all the details that
are necessary for others to
understand your protocol and
also there's like, for Simple if
you add like an amount component
that makes your protocol
scalable, or like a timer
component, and there's like
automatic timers that start when
you use the run functionality.
And there's like a lot of MATLAB
components here, but also
computational components, like
you can put your command lines,
and you can link a few data sets
and things like that. And then,
so every time you create a
protocol, it always starts out
private, you're the only person
who can see it. And then it's up
to you when you want to share it
with who. And you can either
share protocols privately with
others. So if you want to share
it with like close
collaborators, you can share it
privately first. Or if you are
ready to make it fully public,
you can click the Publish
button, and you can make it
fully public. And if you do make
it public, the protocol gets
gets a citation. So it just
keeps the DUI you can include it
in your manuscript editors can
cite it. And we do also archive
all the public protocols with
clocks to ensure long term
preservation. And then you as
the protocol owner, you can
always keep it up to date with
the versioning. And then we also
have something that we call
forks of protocol. so others can
take your protocol and kind of
create their own version of your
protocol. So if there's a couple
of things that they need to
tweak here and there to make it
fit for their needs, they can
take your protocol and create
their own version of your
protocol.
Yeah, but sharing methods is not
always easy. Two questions that
I hear a lot are, one, the
method was developed by someone
else can I share it? And the
other question is, when is the
right time to share the
protocols? Like I think we had
it before a little bit, but
like, what if somebody scoops me
yours, I think if I share too
early. So these are kind of the
two main questions. And
regarding the first question,
there's some very interesting
article for the US Copyright
Office, they have like a whole
kind of page on works that's not
protected by copyright. And I'm
not a lawyer or anything, so I
can not give any legal advice.
But it's very interesting that
they have like an entire section
on methods. So apparently,
methods themselves are not
protected by copyright. So if
you are publishing somebody
else's method, and you put that
person as an author,
technically, that's okay. And
with all the 6000 protocols that
we have on protocols, but I do
we never saw any trouble or any
issues with that. Also, like the
committee on publication ethics,
there's like this phrase that I
think is very interesting, it
says use of similar or identical
phrases and method sections,
where there are limited ways to
describe a common method,
however, it is not uncommon. So
I think it's really, like
oftentimes, we try to formulate
things in our papers like so it
sounds like something different.
And even though if you did the
same thing as somebody else,
like, I think it's really okay
to to see what he did and not
try to make it more complicated
than it already is. And I'm
protocols that I do, we do also
allow you to distinguish
between, excuse me, authors, and
context. So here, you can see,
um, this person was the author
for recipe, but another person
actually published it. And the
context person can always change
in our protocol. So if you
publish somebody else's
protocol, but you're not really
the author, but you can always
transfer the ownership off off
the protocol to somebody else.
So if you leave the lab and you
want to give it to somebody
else, that's totally okay. So we
do make that difference here.
Regarding when to share
protocol. And we do really leave
it up to the users when they
wanted to share protocol. And
when you're sharing, when you're
publishing a protocol, there's
one section where we ask you for
the status of a protocol. So you
can choose between working in
development or other. So you can
choose choose one of the three
and then you can also put the
details. So like whatever that
means for you. So you could say,
this is something we're still
hoping or even I see a lot of
not a lot, but some protocols
where people even say this to
something we tried, and it
didn't work. But here are two
methods that we use. So you can
even share things that didn't
work. So they're out there in
the community. So it's really up
to you when you want to share
protocols. And one thing that I
wanted to share was really
exciting about if all the
protocols are in one central
repository. I'm here somebody
that tweeted they were looking
for, um, for someone who has
experience doing RNA extraction
for neuron core, cortical neuron
cultures, and then there was
like a threat. And somebody
said, from all the ones on
protocols that I Oh, I think
this trisul protocol should work
for your purpose. And if you
look at where this protocol
actually came from, it's a
protocol for sticklebacks,
stickleback fish parasites, so
it has nothing to do with
cortical neuron cultures. Right?
And what I think is really
interesting here is that this
person probably would have never
Even found this protocol if it
wasn't in protocols that I owe,
and nothing is really cool that
you can even find methods that
might not be specifically from
your, from your field. But from
other fields, it could still be
helpful. And I'm coming up from
the time but there's a lot of
organizations, encouraging the
use of protocols that I owe
today that includes a lot of
journals and publishers, we have
more than 500 journals. Now that
added us to their author
guidelines. So they're
encouraging all the authors to
put protocols on protocols that
I owe. And then there's also a
lot of vendors that are
requiring or recommending
protocols that I owe in their
crank guidelines. And also more
and more institutions are
encouraging their researchers to
use protocols that I yo