Unknown: What we're going to be
talking about is the open
canvas. And you say, What is an
open Canvas? Well, I'm here to
tell you. So it is a short
exercise that we'll be asking
you to look at after this call.
It's basically a bunch of boxes
to fill out literally a box
checking exercise. But I found
that it's actually really quite
useful. It's in terms of, if
we're going to keep on going
back to some of the same
sentences about how open project
leaders behave. And in this
case, we're thinking about
designing so open leaders design
and build projects that empower
others to collaborate and
inclusive communities. And what
I mean by this, if you remember
the framework, the open
leadership framework that
malvika referenced in one of our
earlier presentations. So we're
specifically looking at when we
are thinking about our projects,
how do we design our project in
a way that is good for
understanding so people can
understand what's going on. And
so that people can interact with
you effectively, we're designing
our project in a way that helps
us to share things with people,
whether that be gifting some
knowledge, or some ideas or some
software or hardware or whatever
it may be that you are sharing
with people. And we're also
looking at designing in ways
that allow people to
participate. And by the way,
when I share my screen, you
can't see the zoom window in
front of it, can you you can't
see like a level video window. I
know Yes. No, I don't know.
Okay, excellent. Right, because
I have a blocking half of
screen. I didn't want to be
sorry about that. Yes. And the
final thing about the open
Canvas, it helps us write down
and specify our ideas in ways
that make it easy for people to
participate and feel included in
part of the community. So if I
move on to my next screen, that
too far, there we go. Right, the
so this is what an open Canvas
is. And so basically, it is
adapted from the lean canvas. So
if anyone's read, I think the
lean startup, then it has some
ideas about filling out these
boxes, writing down what exactly
it is that you've been thinking
about in your project in terms
of who contributes, how they
contribute, and so on. But I'll
drill down into this a little
bit more in detail. Yeah, people
going to make slides. Okay,
right. So if you see, on the
bottom left, there is
information about the project
execution. And the idea that you
sort of work through step by
step, you talk about who your
contributions are, what they
look like, what your user
profiles may be, so who are you
building your project for? You
move along a bit further, how do
these people contribute
contributed channels? So if you
say I'm thinking about who is
going to be participating my
project? So they need to know,
is this going to be as GitHub is
it going to be some other sort
of platform that I use, and give
information like the unique
value proposition? So why is the
thing that I'm doing interesting
to other people? I'm sort of
hopping around here, I
apologize. But I'll hop over
back for a bit, let's say to the
problem as well. So what are we
solving here? And if so, once
we've stated what the problem
is, what is the solution that's
going to be providing to this
problem.
Apologies for hopping around a
little bit.
We'll move on to the next
slide. So we'll walk through
this in a bit more clear detail.
First of all, on the left, we
have information about the
product. So this is sort of tech
oriented. So what you may be
providing may not necessarily be
a product, it may be a service
or protocol or something like
that. But the end of the day,
it's a thing that you'll be
sharing with other people. And
then on the other side of that
the community is the people who
are going to be using and who
are going to be contributing to
your product. So first of all,
define your problem. So what is
it that you are trying to solve?
And so hopefully, perhaps with
the vision and mission statement
that you've been working on,
you've been thinking about what
this problem is, for us, for
example, if I were to do this
for open life science, the
problem is, science isn't always
as open as I would like it to
be. And then next of all, the
solution in our case will be
this program. I don't think it's
going to solve science entirely.
But I think definitely it helps
to create more people who are
able to work on sharing projects
together. Moving along a bit
further, how will you measure
this? And so again, thinking
through the example of the
organization's program, metrics
might be how many people have
retrained? How many people if we
run a second round? How many
people then go on to be mentors
later on? So you might want to
think about what metrics you can
apply to your project? How would
I measure whether or not my
project is actually being
successful in some way? And then
you think, Okay, so I've got my
big idea. How do I go and create
it, you know, who do I need to
speak to? Do I need to have
computer resources do I need to
have a lab and so depending on
your project, there may be
different things that you need
to start to get towards Working
that project, it may be
networking connections, for
example, I mean, networking
connections in the making
friends with people and
definitely not in the cabling
sense of. So then continuing on,
think about who's contributing,
and what would an ideal
contribution look like? That's
not physically but in terms of
their personalities, their
behaviors. So I might say that a
contribution to open AI science
is a mentor or an expert who can
share their knowledge. Another
type of contributor would also
be the participants you without
this without you, we wouldn't be
going anywhere. And then I say,
whoops. Okay, this is an
overview slide. Sorry. So
contribution profile should
fulfill the first woman windows
covering things should fulfill
the needs required to build your
product. Right? Yeah, that makes
sense. Okay, so basically, the
people who are contributing
should be the people who can
help you get those resources.
And that makes a lot of sense.
Okay, user profiles. So this is
slightly different from your
contributor profiles. So for
example, I suppose in this
scenario, the participants for
open life science might also be
the users. Or we might say that
our users are people who then
learn about open science in the
future from you. So think about
who the target audience for your
project is, and especially who
the early adopters are. So if
you had success, if you said my
project has been openly shared
with someone who would that
person be trying to find that
and contributed channels? Next
question, how do people actually
come to you? How did they
contribute? So in our case, I,
we haven't actually surveyed
you, but my guess would be a lot
of you heard of us through
Twitter. Some of you might have
heard of us through mailing
networks. I know we did some
talks, we did a webinar. So
those will be the contributor
channels for open life science,
and try to think about how you
might gain new contributions for
your channels for your project
as well. And then finally, the
channels for users. So how will
you gain new users that might be
the same way that you gain new
contributions, or it might be a
different way? Maybe you're
doing a training workshop? Try
and think through these
exercises. And I know certainly
when I did a lot of this
personally, I felt like, Okay,
I'm filling this out. But I feel
like I've just been made to fill
out a silly form. But then
afterwards, having filled out
and thought about how I'm going
to fill all this out, I realize
I thought very critically about
my project. And it made me think
and define it in ways that
previously I might not have
effectively done. And there's a
chat message. Okay. Hope
himanshi forgot your laptop
cable. Oh, no. Okay, well, good
luck to you. Hopefully, you can
find your power cable. Okay, and
where was I in my slides? Oh,
yeah. Okay, so community
engagement is talking about the
channels, the other channels and
contributed channels. And
finally, we have our unique
value propositions. So this is
saying, having thought about
whose contribution how they're
contributing, what resources I
need, and what my problems are?
What is the unique value, what
am I offering to the world that
is useful and interesting. And I
like to hear what you offer and
why you are different. I think
that's a really good way of
thinking about that. And then we
have a small example here. This
is for a Mozilla project called
contract contributors, badges
for science, I think that
projects end up being called
paper badger. And so it sort of
gives you a bit of an idea about
how they fought through the
problems, and then added them in
themselves. So saying, there's a
lack of recognition of certain
contribution types and academic
papers, and that people weren't
taking advantage of a web as a
medium, and then just sort of
think through different ways to
solve that to measure that,
basically, by providing budgets
of when people offer papers
based on their contribution. So
someone worked on the software,
someone did the editing, someone
wrote the words, someone did the
lab protocols, and so on. And so
that's a really good example. I
won't go through all of it now.
But the slides are available and
linked to from the agenda. So
you can review it yourself. And
I think that also the demo is in
our notes as well. And oh, but
is that my last slide? No. Okay,
nearly masks. But so if you want
to, this is the link where you
can actually go and access and
open Canvas yourself. So make a
copy of the document, and then
try and see if you can think
through and it's okay, if you
don't feel every single box,
maybe you can't find any boxes,
discuss it with a mental and
they can help you think through
but the bits that you're
missing, but I definitely find
it as a useful exercise to think
about things. And so thinking
back to what we've been doing,
we're trying to empower
researchers and academic leaders
to become Open Science
ambassadors and hopefully this
will help you design and
structure some of your plans for
further on.