Unknown: So I left the FM nasm
research, which is an open
research publishing platform. It
started in 2013. We publish a
range of research outputs all
over the life sciences and
biology, but also broader as
well as traditional research
articles, but also things like
no results, software tools, data
notes, things which hopefully
play in this home making
research more reproducible and
transparent. So we call
ourselves an open research
platform because it will
incorporate these things. The
first is that all articles are
public access. Secondly, we have
a quite strict Open Data policy
don't we endorse, the fair
guidelines are spoken about
earlier. And my Sorry, it's hard
to pin these little things going
about fairly similar with the
with dates of using cars, that
people open technologies and
make sense for people to use.
Again, with methods we have a
method article type that you can
use, but also in your research
article, basically show that the
method is detailed, something
come along and reproduce what
you've done. One I'm really
going to talk to you about today
is to compare every side of it.
And before I really get into it,
I need to sort of flag up a lot
of different things we publish
or someone else published an
open, systematic review, which
looked at how people discuss
open reviews. And I compare it
found there are 122 definitions
of open peer review. And these
22 distinct configurations of
seven traits, there's quite a
lot of different ways that you
can do a compare review. And you
always have to make sure you're
talking about the same open peer
review system. So these are the
seven traits. And I'm not gonna
go into all of them, because
I've only got 10 minutes, I'm
gonna focus on these three. So
open identities. This is the
idea that authors and reviewers
are aware of each other is open
reports, having the review
reports published alongside the
article for people to read. And
the third one is open pre review
manuscripts. These are
preprints. Essentially,
manuscripts are made immediately
available before any formal peer
review procedures. So these are
your bio archive met archives,
all the other archives, and also
is incorporated into our peer
review model as well. So this is
our peer review model. And it is
open pre review manuscripts,
open report open identities. So
when you submit an article to
us, it comes into our editorial
office, we do pre publication
checks, like ethics, plagiarism
is a data there are the methods
complete. And once we're happy
with it, and we send it to be
professionally typeset. Then
within about two weeks, it's
published online sites for the
Doa, indexed in Google Scholar.
And this this point is like the
preprint side of it, because
it's not been peer reviewed, but
it is available online. But you
wouldn't be able to submit it
anywhere else, because you have
committed to Apparently, the
publication of this article
triggers the peer review
process. So we invite referees,
most to agree to review the
article, have their name, their
affiliation, a status for their
report, and their report will
publish online as well. This is
the overall reports and identity
side of it. The officers can go
away submit a second version of
those articles that are based on
those reports from the
reviewers. And that second
version is published October 1.
So this is the loop that you can
see the open pair view and
article revision loop here. And
once that article was to receive
two approved statuses from the
reviewers, so two ticks, or one
approved and two approves with
revisions, so a tip into
question marks at that point,
it's past peer review. So it's
indexed in European cpmc. And
all those bibliographic
databases I want to take you
through so you can see a couple
of examples of how this works.
So this is an article which has
just been published is that the
preprint stage. So you can see
in the title, it says version
one awaiting peer review, that's
included in the citation so you
can see exactly what safeguards
that you know that it's not past
peer review stage. And over here
you can see the open peer review
box. That's where all the names
of the peer reviewers and their
comments will come up. This
articles had a peer review
comment, it's actually purchased
a second version has received
two approved and you can see
that the name the titles
updated, it says what version is
and what's happened with the
peer review.
The review report, you can see
the name of the affiliation, the
comments and behind my face
here. You can see that clip and
respond to the most how many
times invited. So this report
has a dry which means the
reviewer gets credit for Well
done. Because you do put a lot
of effort in when you do these
reports, it's nice to get
credit, you can add it to orchid
IDs, you'll see these things
like that. The whole idea of it
is really to create a nice
constructive dialogue between
the reviewer and the author with
both sides of the parties
standing by their comments. It's
very open and transparent. This
review reports got four people
on it, that's because it's been
co refereed. So this is really
good. If you have early career
researcher who's writing
reviews, and you want to get
credit for it. And you can ride
it with a more senior colleague,
or because maybe it's something
that you both need to work on,
you might have different
expertise, you can work together
as well. And you can see the
response from the author here.
So it's quite a collaborative
process and very transparent.
Once the articles come through
peer review, you can see here it
looks like with the two
versions, the version one had to
approve reservations, the
version twos got to approve up
to the referees have changed
their status from approved for
the patients to approve. So
hopefully, that's quite a quick
one. So you can see why open
peer review can be good. It
minimizes bias. So the reviews
have to stand by the comments.
And also the authors have to
stand by that responses if they
want to clarify anything they
can. And they don't have to
necessarily make everyone happy,
because everyone can see it all
the reviewer reports, it's also
really good information to have
turned anyway, having these
reports open because you can use
it in training if you want to
see how to write a good review
report and also not to write a
review report. And it's if
you're new to the field, and you
want to have a wider context of
that article, you can read those
reports to see what other people
think of it as well. As I
mentioned, the reviewers get
credit for it. And the last
comment is better written, I
realize I should definitely have
a citation here. But there is
some research to show that
review reports to open tend to
be better written than those
that are closed, see if I can
find a citation for that later.
And also, they've been talking a
lot about reproducibility. So
you have a lot of these
different article types, there
tends to be an overemphasis on
research articles, we publish a
lot of research output, so you
get credit for all these
different article types,
including our results and
reproducibility studies. And
this hopefully reduces research
ways to increase efficiencies.
So there isn't someone else out
there trying to do somewhere
that you know, is never gonna
work. There are two things I
quickly want to point out. The
first is study protocols,
because that's coming up later,
we publish them as well. And the
second one, which you can't see,
but it's registered reports.
Register report is basically a
protocol that's published and
peer reviewed prior to any data
being collected. So this enables
you to look at the rigor of the
method. And to ensure that the
research asked which is
published later, is linked back
to the best report and
everything they said in that
mesh report was followed, and
that the data justifies the
conclusions. So hopefully, this
is the end of the SMA line
slide. You can see the F 1000
research is quite open.
Hopefully it sort of increases
the transparency of the way that
research has been published.
It's really quick because we
combine the preprint process
with the peer review process.
And because we asked for the
data and software and also the
reports to be open is quite
reproducible. And so that's it.
Any questions? This is all my my
final slide.