Unknown: open licensing and more
generally, is a fantastic way to
make your your work available to
people to collaborate,
collaborate, especially across
institutions. I've worked inside
of companies that used open
source licensing, just so that
they could collaborate with
other subsidiaries seamlessly.
And so it's it's kind of
incredible the boundaries that
open source allows us to, to
work across. Are these are just
a quick check. Josh, should we
be seeing slides? I think so.
Let me Okay, let me try this
again.
So we can see the cohort called
notes right now.
What that is, I see, I selected
the wrong cat. I'm so sorry.
We see them. Brilliant. Whoo.
Okay.
So this, this is, uh, this is
what I said, This is me. Okay.
So yeah, the the fantastic thing
is, once you've got open
licensing on something, it makes
it so much easier to collaborate
with people, and for people to
build on your work. But I think
largely the folks here, I think
I'm probably preaching to the
choir with that. So I'm going to
move merrily along. So one of
the things that we spoke about
in our breakout session briefly
was that, you know, I may be
specializing and specialized in
open source. And ostensibly, I
have sort of a sense of like
best practices for how to build
a project that's open from the
very beginning. But there are,
but even even given the
expertise that I have, I have
struggled to build open
projects, often time that they
take a little take more
forethought and planning either
than they might otherwise. And
particularly when you're working
on deadlines, sometimes it's
it's, you know, in tech, it's
really unfortunate that often,
you know, things like
accessibility and security, or
open sourcing often end up being
afterthoughts. And so like, my
own experience has shown that to
be true, despite my expertise.
So I think I really just want to
implore people to plan ahead of
time to, to take the time to
think about these things so that
you can build for an open
project from the very beginning.
Because ultimately, the reason
we do open source and open
licensing is because the values
outweigh the the the costs of
doing that planning. But we just
need to sort of Route ourselves
in our commitment to being open,
so that we do take that time
upfront to make it happen.
So a huge when people talk about
open source, they're often it's
a term that's a little
overloaded. Open Source
tactically, just speaks to
licensing, right? An open source
license is a license that
conforms to the Open Source
Definition, talk a little bit
more about that later. And so
there are open source projects
that are out there, that people
will just put an open license on
it. But they may not actually
accept the interested in
collaborating with people, maybe
they just wanted to share it. Or
maybe they they are interested
in collaborating with people,
but only people within their
organization. And so often, when
I think about open source, I
think about three really
important aspects of it. First
is the licensing. And because
that everything sort of flows
from from that. But the second
is the sort of the collaboration
model. When people think about
open source, it's, they're often
implying something about the way
that people collaborate around a
project. That is that the source
code and the assets are freely
available and inspectable. And
that anybody can open a pull
request or raise an issue, and
then that'll be triage and
accepted from the community. The
last component is not just open
collaboration, but open
governance. And this is this is
one of the more tricky aspects.
But you know, for instance,
let's look at the Google's
Android open source project.
It's an open source project, it
is under an open source license.
But it does not use the open
collaboration model, because
they don't accept pull requests
or issues from people outside of
the company. And it's not openly
governed, because well, it's it
is a Google project and they
decide everything that goes on
with it. You compare that to
projects like NumPy or Sai pi,
where these are projects that
are under open source licenses,
they are owned, or they have an
open collaboration model. And
they're also governed by
foundations and nonprofits, that
has like an open governance
scaffolding. So there are ways
to not just be a contributor,
but ultimately to join the
technical steering committee or
participate in decisions about
the outcomes of the project. So
I just want to unpack open
source broadly, because it means
a lot of different things to
different people. And you can
see how those three facets can
contribute to sometimes the
misunderstandings, and it's
really important for us to
understand what our intent is
what level of openness we're
working towards, when we're
building a project. Suffice it
to say, a successful open source
project is a lot more than just
an open source license. And
there are a lot of details here
that are included. Like, you
know, at the beginning of the
call, we mentioned the code of
conduct. You know, I've been
planning and there's so much
that goes into it. But let's
not, let's not get overwhelmed
with it is you know, one step at
a time as we build open
projects. So all open licenses
share these three things in
common. The Free Software
Foundation has like the four
freedoms, the Open Source
Definition has the the tin, tin
clauses that things must be
compliant with to become open
source. But ultimately, they all
share three things in common.
Anyone can use the word for any
purpose, that anyone can modify
the work, and people can share
that work freely as well.
In any license, there are both
the rights that you get, as well
as the responsibilities, no
matter how simple or brief the
licenses any effective license.
Certainly any OSI approved
license is going to have both of
those sections, there are there
are open style licenses out
there, like the beer ware
license or the WTF Pl miticides,
do whatever the you want. And
those are essentially considered
to be like the WTF PL license is
considered to most likely be
most similar to like a public
domain commitment. And
interestingly, public domain is
not open source. There's an
interesting literature around
that. And that cc zero is also
not open source. But it's but
it's a good, it's a good thing.
So I'm never gonna dissuade
people from using it, the
history there's complex. But as
I was saying, there are rights
and responsibilities. And often
one of the responsibilities that
comes with an open license is
the responsibility of
attribution. So that means, you
know, declaring who the who the
original author was, or where
you got it from and linking back
to that you'll often notice in
particularly like in your
software applications, that
question I'll get to that in
just a moment, you'll often
notice if if you in the software
that you use, there's there's
usually like, you know, an about
screen. And in that about
screen, there's often a
declaration of attribute of open
source licenses and attribution.
And so that is where that
software maker is honoring their
responsibility to, to attribute
CC by is a license. In fact, all
of the all of the Creative
Commons licenses are licenses,
even cc zero, which is in, in
practice, effectively, a
commitment to the public domain
is also a copyright license. So
all of these are licenses that
are spelling out your rights,
and all but cc zero really, also
spell out your responsibilities.
Because cc zero is sort of a
commitment to the public domain,
there is no responsibility,
there is no requirement for
attribution. There is no
copyright holder, they've sort
of disclaimed their ownership at
that point. But But again, these
are all copyright licenses,
they're they're hacks on the
copyright system. And so, you
know, even the copyleft things
or the public domain cc zero
things, though, they're
copyright licenses, there's
they're explicitly about just
claiming the copyright. So I
mentioned copyleft. And broadly
speaking, in open source, there
are two broad subsets of
licenses. There are the
permissive licenses are non
reciprocal, and there are
definitely different words used
here. Sometimes the words have
baggage. So I try to be pretty
even handed in how I describe
them. permissive licenses like
MIT BSD, the Apache License 2.0.
They don't require. So say you
take a piece of software, and
you make a derivative work from
it, you modify it. In a
permissive license, you are not
required to share your
modifications under that same
license, you can license them
differently, you can license
them under proprietary license.
That's, that's totally up to
you. And it's, it's your
prerogative to decide what you
want to do there. On the other
side, we have copyleft licenses.
And even in this category,
there's a continuum from from
weak to strong copyleft. And
these are sometimes called
reciprocal licenses, because I,
as someone who has authored,
say, a GPL, v3 software that you
are now using, and you are now
modifying and creating
derivative works with, because
it's under the GPL, v3, you are
have a responsibility to provide
your modifications under that
very same license. And there's
things out there like the A GPL,
which is a strong copyleft
license that specifically speaks
to software that operates over a
network. Ultimately, these are
all valid and good licenses and
picking one. Don't worry, it
doesn't need to be too
complicated. But ultimately, you
will need to make a decision
about depending on the use case
of your project, what what is
appropriate for you.
So open source is really all
about copyright. It's not about
trademark. And, of course, there
are at least three areas of
intellectual property law,
there's there's copyright,
there's trademark, and then
there's also patents. Largely
open source licenses don't say
much about patents. Some of them
do explicitly, this explicitly
include a patent grant, to the
people who are using that
software. The precedent that the
whole industry is operating
under right now is that even if
an open source license doesn't
explicitly include a patent
grant, the operating assumption
is that there is an implicit
patent grant, at the very least.
So I know that patents and
especially in context of
academia, there's a question of
tech transfer translation. How
does this technology How does
this work that get translated
to, to do industry or to
something that will drive
impact. And I know that I was
recently at Johns Hopkins,
trying to help help some of
their good people in their
library, persuade their tech
tech transfer people that, you
know, open licensing is not,
there's not to be feared. And so
anywho patents are often one of
the things that people get a
little, you know, people who are
not used to open licensing, they
can be sort of afraid of the
prospects here. But suffice it
to say, patents, there's an
implicit if not an explicit
patent grant, when you put an
open license on something, it
doesn't mean that you can't
patent things, it just means
that you're there's there's a
grant that's flowing through
that license. So there are
happily tools and resources out
there to help you navigate
choosing a license. Choose a
licensed calm is pretty great.
Creative Commons has a lot of
really plain language,
explanations of the different
licenses that they have. The
number one thing that I would
recommend is looking not only
looking at these resources, but
if you are creating a project or
you know writing some code to to
analyze some results, or
whatever the case may be. Look
at the licenses that are common
in the community you're
releasing the code into. So in
the JavaScript ecosystem, it's
often the NIT or the BSD
license. In the PHP ecosystem,
or in Java, it's often the
Apache License. And like there's
no value judgment on those
things. It just happens to be
sort of common practice within
those communities to use a given
license. And so if you're
looking for collaboration and
participation from people in
that community, you know,
abiding the community norms is a
pretty, pretty solid way to
start engaging with them. So
consider both what is typical in
that community, as well as what
the specific constraints and
goals are of your project, and
these resources will help you
narrow data, there's decisions.
So open source is really, really
just about code, which is, you
know, obviously, the work that
we all do is so much bigger than
just software. We deal with
data, we deal with imagery, we
deal with other all manner of
assets, we deal with hardware.
There are open source hardware
licenses. In the Creative
Commons does a fantastic job of
providing licenses for open open
data and sort of open content.
So whether it's for the white
paper, or the textbook, or the
data set that goes along with a
project, Creative Commons is
really, really fantastic sort of
catch all set of licenses. And
of course, there are variations
that include, you know, require
attribution, or require you to
share your code, the derivative
works in the same way. And then
there are ones that even our
have a non commercial clause, of
course, once we add non
commercial classes, well, that
gets even further from open
source and open licensing,
because then we're making
judgments and putting
restrictions on who can who can
really use it. So there's a
question here about what happens
when we import multiple
libraries from other projects,
and which licenses apply to the
work that we're creating? So
this is a really good question.
There are two triggers, in
licenses, generally, to be aware
of
one trigger is distribution,
which is like the moment that
you are distributing the
software, whether that's, you
know, I'm running it on a web
server, and you're using it or,
or I'm sending you software
that's on a disk, or I'm sending
you a little robot or a little
sensor that has software I built
on it, those all count is forms
of distribution. And the
distribution. Usually, that's
where some of the
responsibilities kick in, like
the attribution, or the
requirement to share your work
in the same way. When you
inevitably end up using software
that's licensed multiple
different ways. The one that
applies to you. No, apologies
only backup. So first
distribution, second is the
derivative works. And then copy
and copy left, the moment you
make a derivative work. And that
means really modifying that
software. So if you look at the
Linux operating system, there's
broad agreement under and
understanding that if I modify
the Linux operating system
itself, that's me creating a
derivative work. And therefore,
the software because it's under
a copyleft license, the software
I create needs to be shared
under that same license.
However, if I'm building an
application on top of Linux, you
know, similar to like, Okay, I'm
not modifying windows, but I'm
building software for people who
use Windows, same thing, Linux,
Mac OS, what have you. If I'm
building something in the user
space on Linux, that's not a
derivative work. And so I'm not
required to distribute my work
under the license that that
Linux is under, which is GPL,
v2. So the most restrictive
license isn't necessarily the
one apply that applies to your
work, you have to ask yourself
two questions. What are you
distributing? And what are you
deriving your work from? And
those are obviously like, not
always trivial questions to come
up with answers with. But there
are lots of good people in the
community who are happy to
provide advice on these things.
Obviously, always recommend
speaking to legal counsel. But I
will also say that the Open
Source Initiative does a lot of
low key consulting for people.
You know, whether it's the, you
know, the EU in their copyright
directive or the US and their
Federal Open Source policy, are
various agencies trying to
figure out how to use open
source or universities doing the
same. There are we exist, and
we're happy to help provide
guidance. So here are a number
of resources that I think there
are a few that were already
included here. I added a couple,
a few myself. These are
excellent resources for getting
more information, both about the
licensing, and more generally
building open source
communities. Open Source guide
is one that I've added here
that's specific that includes
questions of licensing, but also
like okay, how do I build a
community around this? What are
really the key components of the
community Code of Conduct is a
great start. But what about the
governance? How do we recognize
our contributors? How do I set
expectations with the community?
What expectations do they need
me to set? You know, all of
these questions, I'm happy to
say are like not new. And so
there's a lot of prior art out
there to help provide guidance
on these matters. For your
future with open source, I
apologize. That's that's a
that's a book. It's not open
source book either. And further
apologies disclaimer is written
by a good friend of mine. But it
is a really, it's it is the only
book that is written
specifically for newcomers to
open source. And I think it has
a lot of really useful
information in that regard.
Producing OSS is a book that is
open source from Karl Fogel when
the former directors of the Open
Source Initiative, incredibly
useful information. And I'd be
remiss if I didn't underscore
the Open Source Definition there
at the top. That is, of course,
the definition of the
organization and a part of
stewards and uses to judge
whether a new license is open
source or not.
So I think
I think that's the extent of
what I've got for you. And I
apologize, I think I might have
gone over time, but I hope that
was useful.