Unknown: I'm a PhD student I
used to I study how the Open
Science how our movement can
contribute to democratize
science and technology,
especially in the global south.
And I have other power projects
that if you want to, you can
contact me I can tell you about.
So just to start, sorry, let's
go there. So science, you know
this better than anyone
but
also mostly in life science, but
science, humans tools, you can
do anything, if you you can
produce data, if you have your
tools, which are super wide
variety of rights, like analog
tools, electronic tools, what
tools as as we are not only
talking about electronics, which
is the first image that appears
there when we talk about open
hardware. But all the tools we
use in the scientific process in
this research process, we could
say 99%, today, they are closed.
And when we say they're closed,
we're talking about that the
designs of the tools, the
blueprints, how to have the tool
is not available for anyone but
the vendor. So this is like the
equivalent of proprietary
software, let's say. And this
brings some problems for
researchers and for society in
general. So especially for for
researchers, one of the problems
is that when you don't have
access to the design of or to
understand how your two words we
call that is a black box. It's
complicated when you don't fully
understand how the process of
sample to data is performed.
This has some problems not only
for the for the research and
knowledge production process
itself, but also for example,
when this equipment breaks down,
and you have to wait for the
supplier to repair it, and you
have a big delay waiting times
for because you're probably not
a big force to push for the
vendor to come and repair your
your equipment. This is
especially more difficult in
countries where that are not far
away from the from the factories
or from the centers where these
tools are produced. Another
another pain, let's say is that
the tools are very difficult to
customize. And usually in
science, you want to customize
your tools. Because if you're
doing cutting edge research,
then you know what you need. And
it will be it's the case of many
researchers that they want to
tweak their tools. And it's very
difficult for them because first
of all, they have to reverse
engineering what they already
have, which implies open
equipment or trying to
understand how it works, there's
a lot of time that if they had
the blueprints, this will be
time saved. Another thing is
that usually it's really
expensive. And again, this is
feeding the knowledge gap that
we have between global north and
global South countries, there is
a lot of science production in
global north countries. And
there is not so much in the
global south countries because
it's mainly many, many factors.
But one big factor is that
people don't have access to
equipment equipment is very
expensive. So all this pains
that are derived from having
closed hardware are a reality.
And it's something that people
have been addressing for a long
time. But the good news is that
people make tools. And in the
last 10 years, let's say there,
there has been a big wave of
people all around the world
building and building different
kinds of artifacts, not only for
science artifacts in general,
there are many factors for
explaining this. One of the most
important factors is the 3d
printing revolution, let's say
because most of these artifacts
are combinations of 3d printed
parts and low cost electronics.
So another factor is that
electrons nowadays are quite
accessible. And another
important thing is that the
arrival of boards easy boards,
like Arduino allowed not only
researchers but people in
general allowed people to tweak
electronics to play with them
too. As your was mentioning, do
an iterative process over
electronics, improving the
designs trying You don't have to
be able to solder in order to
try things so everything is
becoming easier, and people are
just building stuff. So in this
slide, you see some of the open
hardware for science designs
that I wanted to showcase. In
general the rule is that if you
needed probably someone has
started experimenting with it,
and there is a design somewhere
in the internet that you will be
able to find. Um, so I'm showing
there the other month or the
month is an open device open
acoustics device that people use
it for monitoring noises in the
audible and non audio spectrum.
So it's a center biologist
working in conservation and
ecology in general. The other
one is
a very high tech device, which
is an open AFM and atomic force
microscope. And this is
developed by mpfl, Amazon
researchers working on a
laboratory of nano and bio
instrumentation. Again, they
have been dealing with closed
materials all the time, and they
work on developing
instrumentation. So they wanted
to, they reverse engineer
everything they could, and they
wanted to document it. So people
don't want to have to go through
that all over again, every time.
The third one open frog is
microfluidics platform developed
by Goldie labs. And the
interesting part about this is
that also the open drop is part
of a big set for bio open
biology instrumentation
developed by gaue labs to so you
can go there to link and check
it. Open flex shirt is a is a
microscope that is being used
right now to detect malaria very
easily. And in a very cheap way.
In Ghana, and in other, I think
in Peru coming soon. Open museum
is a very precise scale, that,
again, is open hardware. And
like your brains is a company
that makes open hardware,
neuroscience, neuroscience,
sorry, neuroscience experiments,
to teach neuroscience to kids at
schools in a cheap and easy way.
So all of these equipments, and
these are just examples are open
science hardware tools that have
some advantages over the
proprietary ones. In general,
and this is not Oh, sorry. I was
seeing the chat. We use backyard
tools in our rain. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, but your tools is super,
super popular. super nice. So
um, some some characteristics of
open hardware? Or why are people
building stuff? In general, open
hardware for science is more
affordable than proprietary
options. So this doesn't mean
that it's low cost, because
there is a big preconception and
misconception about open
hardware that all open hardware
is low cost, do it yourself, and
therefore it's associated with
less quality. And it's a it's a
common question that I get, like
from from researchers saying and
kind of published by very nature
using open science, Howard?
Well, yeah, we can. And there
are, like people are using open
zine forward to publish in in
journals, but no problem at all.
This leads me to another
important fact, that means that
if we know how tools work, then
we can talk about real
reproducibility. So we usually
try to push open hardware into
open science discussions,
because for us, it's pretty
important that in this whole
reproducibility crisis, we talk
about tools, right? If we know
which are the tools that people
are using, then we can
absolutely reproduce what they
have done in their research.
Another important thing, as I
was mentioning before, is that
this is repairable. So if this
is why universities are seeing
open, how are we good eyes right
now. Because if you have a fab
lab, which is something common
at university, and you have
techie people there and you your
tool is open hardware, then
maybe someone there can help you
repair it, and you have less
lace, and you have less waiting
times for you to use the
equipment again. And then
there's the learning and find
loads of people develop tools,
because it's a lot of fun. And
also because they can customize
and tweak instruments a bit just
to experiment with new things
without this, this waiting
times. Another benefit that is
usually overlooked a bit when
when we give talks for academics
and researchers is that it's
not. It's a big thing for people
in the global south. It's a big
thing when you have really small
budgets to do your research. And
suddenly with the same money,
instead of having one tool to do
your analysis, you have 10. And
we're talking of these orders of
magnitude, in terms of reduction
of costs. There are there is
research on this, where people
say there is a 90% reduction of
cost in equipment. So it's not
it's not as more often. So there
are lots of people doing open
houses for science. And I would
say most of them now are
gathering a community called
Global Open Science our or gosh,
this is a community of which was
created like the first gathering
was in 2016. Then we have
another gathering in Chile and
2017 and China in 2018. There is
the manifesto that you can check
online. I will give you the
links afterwards. But the idea
of this is that there is a
roadmap of the community and
everything is very, very simple.
disgust because it's a very
diverse community. The idea is
making Open Science how
ubiquitous by 2025, which is a
super ambitious goal, but we're
not
that far. So it's something to
take into account. And there are
lots of resources that you can
use within this community. So
what can you do if you think
that you could benefit from
using open science hardware or
you want to learn more about it.
So you can join the discussion
in our forum, it's a very
friendly space. Don't be afraid
You don't have to be expert in
electronics at all. Most people
are not most people here learn
on the internet with peers. You
can document if you have a
development and different
platforms, many people use, of
course, GitHub for software, but
they also use it for uploading
designs of electronics and 3d
printed parts. There are
specific platforms for this that
are now more than ever. Docker
breaks is one key reason other
some people do it an Open
Science Framework to you can
follow open heart leaders,
sorry, which is our program for
supporting people who are making
open science, how we're in
science, and auto science. And
there is also a journal that is
managed by the community, the
Journal of open hardware and
special thing about it also,
besides being a community
journal, of course, open access
is that we review the designs
which is not common, right. So
you submit your source files,
and we take a look at them and
we make sure that everything you
have there is open and available
to everyone. So some useful
links, I leave them there you
have the links to the slides in
the notes. We have a
collaborative list of resources
for open hardware fills in
GitHub, feel free please to edit
and comment. There is a lot of
coming for Open Sans how
community in 2020 in terms of
residences in terms of projects
that are scaling a bit and feel
free again to go to the Gar
form, just drop your question or
contact me directly. If you
don't want to go to a forum,
just send me a message on
Twitter or send me an email.
totally open to it.